(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-02T13:59:17.024602",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
のーじゃー！
Noja!
あららら　みらみら　あちち　めらー！
Oh my, mira mira, achichi, mera!
ホロライブあそびまわり隊　ゴリラクター担当の　引けしやおらマンだー！
Hololive Asobi Mawari-tai's gorilla-actor in charge, Hikeshiya Oraman!
あちちめらなのだのじゃー！
It's Achichi Meira, noja!
ついにこの日が　ついにこの日が来てしまったのじゃー
Finally, this day has finally come, noja.
ホラーゲームでが　やってきましたのじゃー！
The horror game has arrived, noja!
うん　緊張してるからお面つけてるのじゃ
Yeah, I'm wearing a mask because I'm nervous, noja.
ちょホラーゲーム怖いらしい　怖いらしい
I heard horror games are scary, scary.
でも八番出口は　ホラーゲームの中じゃと怖くないらしいていう　聞く
But I heard that Exit 8 isn't as scary as other horror games.
本当に事前情報一コマ入れてない
I haven't taken in any pre-release info at all.
何が起こるかも知らない
I don't know what might happen.
そんな怖くない？　怖くない？　大して？　え怖くない？
Not that scary? Not scary? Not really? Eh, not scary?
むしろ八番出口　見たことあるの？　怖い？　怖くない？
Have you actually seen Exit 8? Is it scary? Not scary?
でもそれわし知ってるよ　わし知ってるよそれ
But I know that, you know. I know that.
あのさ　あのさ　辛いの得意な人がさ　あのカレーの甘口をさ
You know, when people who are good with spicy food eat mild curry...
ちょっと辛いカレーの甘口をさ　辛くないってやつと一緒じゃろ？
Eating slightly spicy mild curry is like saying it's not spicy, right?
ホラーゲームではない？　えホラーと思えない？
Isn't it a horror game? Can't you think of it as horror?
何？　誰を信じればいいのじゃわしは
What? Who should I believe, noja?
違う？
Am I wrong?
そんなじゃな　あジャンルがホラーじゃない？
Not like that. Ah, is the genre not horror?
あジャンルがホラーじゃないんじゃの　入門編
Ah, the genre isn't horror? An introductory edition.
間違い探し？　間違い探し　なるほど
Spot the difference? Spot the difference, I see.
わかったのじゃ　じゃ間違い探しだと思ってやるのじゃ
I get it, noja. Then I'll do it thinking it's spot-the-difference.
でもちょっとお主らにね　最初にね謝っておきたいことが
But first, there's something I want to apologize to you all about.
謝る部屋行くか　ちょ謝る部屋行くのじゃ
Let's go to the apology room. Let's go to the apology room, noja.
ちょ謝る部屋行くのじゃ　あのあのあの記憶力自信なし
Let's go to the apology room, noja. Um, um, um, zero confidence in my memory.
記憶力に自信ないのじゃ
I have no confidence in my memory, noja.
わし記憶力に自信が本当にないのじゃ
I really have no confidence in my memory, noja.
昨食べたごはん　すら覚えてない
I don't even remember what I ate yesterday.
うん　あの　20回とか繰り返せば覚えるのじゃ
Yeah, um, if I repeat it like 20 times, I'll remember it, noja.
ジオゲッサーの電柱覚えてるじゃろって言われると想うんだが　あれすっごい頑張って覚えたのじゃ
You might say I remember the utility poles in GeoGuessr, but I memorized those by trying super hard, noja.
あの、短期記憶
Um, short-term memory...
短期記憶自信なし。
Zero confidence in short-term memory.
短期記憶にほんとに自信がないのですのじゃ。
I really have zero confidence in my short-term memory, you see.
つまり？ つまり、ちょっと、あの、間違い探しゲーガチ自信なしですのじゃ。
Meaning? Meaning, like, um, I seriously have zero confidence at finding differences in games, you see.
ガチ自信なしですのじゃ。
I seriously have zero confidence, you see.
うん。ちょっとそれだけ、それだけ。
Yeah. Just... just that. Just that.
ちょっと事前、事前にね、事前にね、自信なしですのじゃ。
Just beforehand, beforehand, beforehand, you see, I have no confidence.
つまり今日のラストはなんだっけ…あー忘れちゃったな、記憶力なさすぎって言われたらヘコむから、ヘコむから最初に謝っとくのじゃ。うん。
Meaning today's last part was... what was it? Ah, I forgot. If people say my memory is terrible, it'll make me depressed, so I'll apologize first. Yeah.
記憶力自信なし！
Zero confidence in my memory!
結構違いわかりやすい。あ、なんか…
The differences are pretty easy to tell. Ah, wait...
すっごくわかりやすいならいけるのじゃ。すっごくわかりやすいならいけるのじゃ。
If it's super easy to tell, I can do it. If it's super easy to tell, I can do it.
長い夜になりそう、そんな…
It's gonna be a long night, no way...
耐久？そんなむずいのじゃ。そのむずいのじゃ。
Endurance? That's so hard. That's so hard.
あそういえばさ、そういえばお主らさ、今日さ…
Oh, come to think of it, you guys, today...
ホロライブ公式からさ、ハロウィンボイス出たんだけど、ハロウィンボイス出たんだけど聞いた？知ってる？
Hololive official released Halloween voices, did you hear them? Do you know?
ハロウィンボイス出たんだけど…
Halloween voices came out, but...
ハロウィンボイス2026もう手に入れてくれたのじゃ？
Did you already get Halloween Voices 2026?
挨拶違った。あそう。
Wait, wrong greeting. Oh right.
あのね、デビュー前に撮ったのじゃ。デビュー前に撮ったから、デビュー前に撮ったからね、挨拶とかも違くてね、
You know, I recorded it before my debut. Because I recorded it before my debut, the greetings and stuff are different,
喋り方はそんな違くないかもって思うんじゃが…うん。
so I thought my speaking style wouldn't be that different, but... yeah.
デビューする前のお主が聴けるのじゃ。
You can hear me before my debut.
ハロウィンボイスが出てるのじゃ。あの公式Xで、わしのTwitterでも宣伝してるから聞いてほしいのじゃ。
Halloween voices are out. I'm promoting it on my official X and my Twitter, so I want you to listen to it.
なんか、なんじゃっけ？えっとね…
What was it again? Um...
滞在？滞在じゃない、7つの甘罪？7つの甘い罪みたいなのがコンセプトっぽくて、
Staying? Not staying, 7 sweet sins? It seems the concept is about 7 sweet sins,
わしの罪？なんか罪のテーマみたいなのがあって、わしのテーマが色欲？
my sin? There's a sin theme, and my theme is lust?
色欲なのじゃ。かんざい？
It's lust. Lust?
かんざい、7つのかんざい？甘いに罪と書いて…うん。
Lust, seven lusters? Writing sweet and sin... yeah.
そう、滞在に沿ったテーマ。意外だった。
Yes, the theme fit my stay. It was surprising.
なんか、あの…なんで？なんかね、罪を選ぶみたいなのを、お任せにしたら、罪を選ぶみたいなのを、お任せにしたのじゃ。
Somehow, um... why? Like, when I left it up to them to choose the sin, they just assigned me one.
なんでもいいのじゃって言ったら、あの色欲になったのじゃ。うん。
When I said "anything is fine," I ended up with lust. Yeah.
貸借不一致？わからんよー！
Balance mismatch? I don't get it!
わからんよー！聞いてみてから判断するのじゃ。サンプルがあるっぽいから…
I don't get it! You should listen to it and judge for yourself. There seems to be a sample...
なんかコスプレしたよ？コスプレしたのじゃ。うん。コスプレをしましたのじゃ。
I did cosplay? I did cosplay. Yeah. I did cosplay.
サンプルがあるから、配信終わったらサンプル聞いてね。
There's a sample, so after the stream ends, go listen to the sample,
よいなと思ったら是非ゲットしてほしいのじゃ。
and if you think it's good, I'd definitely love for you to get it.
人間って色欲持ち上げすぎじゃない？欲の中の1つじゃろ？
Don't humans hype up lust too much? It's just one of the desires, right?
なんか人間って過度に色欲を持ち上げるイメージがありますのじゃ。なぜ？
It feels like humans excessively hype up lust. Why?
空気読みでも思ったんじゃが、サラマンダーにはない感覚。
I thought so during the reading too, it's a sensation salamanders don't have.
意外な一面、確かに意外な一面が見れるかも？のじゃ。
An unexpected side, maybe you can see an unexpected side, you see.
なぜなのかなのじゃ。いよいよ宣伝したのじゃ。そろそろゲームの方始めようかな。
Why is that, you see. I've finished promoting. Time to start the game soon.
8番出口！
Exit 8!
始めようかなって思うんじゃが、
I was thinking of getting started...
お主ら、準備はいいかの？
Are you guys ready?
いい感じなのだじゃ？
Is everything looking good?
じゃあ、ここから、えっと、8番出口っていうゲームで遊んでいこうと思うので、
So, from here, I'm thinking of playing a game called The Exit 8.
ゲームが見たくて、わしの素顔が見たいお主らは、高評価をするのじゃ！
If you want to see the game and my real face, smash that like button!
サラマンダーを高評価で育てるのじゃ！お願いするなのだじゃ！
Raise Salamander with likes! I'm counting on you!
お願いするなのだじゃ、おめんとってほしい人は高評価するなのだじゃ！
I'm counting on you, everyone who wants me to take off my mask, hit that like button!
した？しましたのじゃ？
Did you? Did you do it?
十回、グスはだめなのだじゃ。グスをしたらなくなっちゃうのじゃ、奇数回を押してほしいのじゃ。
Ten times? Even numbers are no good. It disappears, so please press an odd number of times.
よし、よしよし、じゃあ、育ててもらったところで、初めていこうと思いますのじゃ！
Alright, then since you've raised it for me, I think I'll get started!
よいしょ！
Here we go!
のじゃ。
Right.
のじゃ？
Right?
よいしょ。
There we go.
のじゃ。
Right.
ちょっと待て、の？
Wait a second.
Wait just a second.
うん。
Hm.
音量が……
The volume is...
乗っている？
Playing?
ジーーって聞こえる？
Can you hear a buzzing sound?
ジーーって聞こえる、お主ら？
Can you hear a buzzing sound, you guys?
ジーーって音乗ってる？
Is there a buzzing sound playing?
ゲームの音なんじゃが。
It's the game audio.
聞こえる？
Can you hear it?
聞こえない？何？聞こえる人と聞こえない人がいる。これもち異変なのだじゃ？
Can't you? What? Some people hear it and some don't. Is this also an anomaly?
これもち異変？
Is this also an anomaly?
よいしょ。
There we go.
音量はどうじゃろうか？
How is the volume?
このジャージャーって音とかも。
Even this buzzing sound and stuff.
歩いてないとそこまでわかんない。
I won't really know unless I'm walking.
よし、じゃあ、
Alright, then...
やってみて判断するのじゃ。
Try it out and judge.
聞こえた？
Did you hear it?
ジーーって音。
That buzzing sound.
えっと、
Um,
どっちが前？
Which way is forward?
さすがにこっちか。
Naturally, it's this way.
ちっちゃい？
Too small?
これぐらい？
About this much?
おっきい？
Too big?
歩いてみて。
Try walking.
これぐらい？
About this much?
どう？
How is it?
最初お手本？
First, the example?
わかったのじゃ。
I get it.
これぐらい？じゃあこれぐらいにしてみますのじゃ。
About this much? Then let's try making it about this much.
よし。
Alright.
始めるのじゃ！
Let's start!
ええとね、ルールはえっと、
Umm, the rules are, um...
暗記げっぽいのかじゃ、自信のない暗記げ、なんかこういう広告とか？
It's like a memory test? A memory test I'm not confident in. Like these ads?
エイト歯科医院とか、あの上のね、
Eight Dental Clinic, and the ones above...
上の天井とか床とかいろんなものを見て
Looking at the ceiling, the floor, and various other things,
い変を見つけるらしいのじゃ。
apparently we find anomalies.
目。
Eyes.
防犯カメラ。
Security camera.
覚える。覚える？何を？
Memorize. Memorize what?
え、もっと頑張ったほうがいいのかじゃ？従業員専用、
Uh, should I try harder? Employee-only,
従業員専用、分電盤室、
Employee-only, distribution board room,
分電盤室、
Distribution board room,
分電盤室！
Distribution board room!
従業員専用、清掃員詰所、
Employee-only, janitor's room,
消化栓、避難誘導じゃあ！
fire hydrant, evacuation guide!
そして、広告も覚える！防犯カメラ作動中！
And also memorize the ads! Security camera in operation!
これ何？ムーブフェス、フェス！
What is this? Move Fes, Fes!
えっと、メイクアップ！
Um, makeup!
えっと、司法書士！
Um, judicial scrivener!
相談？えっと、これはドッグサロン、ドッグ！
Consultation? Um, this is Dog Salon, Dog!
アルバイトパート大募集！
Part-time jobs urgently needed!
時給は1000円。
Hourly wage is 1,000 yen.
東京って今ここどこなんじゃろうな。
I wonder where in Tokyo this place is right now.
時給1000円でいいのかじゃ？この世界ではいいのかじゃ？
Is 1,000 yen an hour fine? Is that fine in this world?
エイト歯科医院、は、歯医者は世界一おいって言う、
Eight Dental Clinic, ha, dentists are the number one place in the world, they say.
コンビニよりおいってきくのじゃ。
I hear it's better than convenience stores.
よし、行くのじゃ。
Alright, let's go.
走るもするっぽいのかじゃ。
It looks like we can run too.
エモ覚える？
Memorize emotes?
うーん、たぶん、オッケー。
Um, probably okay.
いったい行ってみるのじゃ！
Let's go try it out!
禁煙。
No smoking.
タバコ。
Tobacco.
テンジブロック。
Braille block.
左側通行だって。わかったのじゃ。
It says keep left. Understood.
キープレフト！
Keep left!
行ってみるのじゃ。
Let's try going.
よいしょよいしょよいしょよいしょ、よいしょよいしょよいしょ、監視カメラもあるのじゃ。
Here we go, here we go, here we go, there's also a surveillance camera.
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ
Heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho...
のじゃ？
Huh?
あ、人がいる
Ah, there's a person.
え、ねえ、人いたらダメ？
Wait, hey, is it bad if there's a person?
人いたらダメなのじゃ？
Is it bad if there's a person?
禁煙
No smoking.
人いたら 人いへん？ 人はいへんじゃない？
If there's a person... wait, shouldn't there be no person?
いったん行ってみるか
Let's check it out for a moment.
えっと、歯医者、歯医者
Um, dentist, dentist.
え、これ順番とかある？
Wait, is there an order to these?
歯医者、パート、ドッグ、司法書士、メイク
Dentist, part-time jobs, dog salon, judicial scrivener, makeup...
なんかそんな変わってない気がするのじゃ
Doesn't feel like anything changed.
んで、分...分電盤室
And, elec... electrical room.
分電盤室、従業員専用、清掃員詰所
Electrical room, staff only, janitor's room...
なんか全然普通、普通な気がする
It feels completely normal.
普通な気がする消火栓
Fire hydrant feels normal.
防犯カメラ作動中！
Security camera in operation!
セキュリティカメラ、特になんか変なとこない気がする
Security camera... doesn't feel like anything's weird.
変なとこない気がするよ、のじゃ？
Doesn't feel like anything's weird, huh?
でもあんま細かいとこ言われたらわかんないのじゃ
But if you mention tiny details, I won't know.
行くのじゃ！行くのじゃ！
Let's go! Let's go!
ねえ、自分の足音怖い。自分の足音怖い
Hey, my own footsteps are scary. My own footsteps are scary.
え、何もない！異変ない、異変ない！
Wait, nothing's here! No anomaly, no anomaly!
余裕。振り向く
Piece of cake. Turn around.
異変ない！異変ない、異変ない！
No anomaly! No anomaly, no anomaly!
左側通行
Keep left.
何もない！え、じゃあ1回で行けるのじゃ？
Nothing's there! Wait, can I make it on the first try?
まだ何も怖くないのじゃ
Still not scared at all.
あ、おじさん来た
Ah, the middle-aged man is here.
おじさんいるから異変じゃない
There's an old man, so it's not an anomaly.
禁煙ある。禁煙あったのじゃ
No smoking sign is there. There was a no smoking sign.
歯医者あったのじゃ
There was a dentist.
えーと、パート大募集もあったのじゃ
Um, part-time job recruitment was there too.
分電盤室もある。ドックオープンもある。司法書士もあるのじゃ
Electrical room is there. Dog salon opening is there. Judicial scrivener is there too.
メイクアップアートもあったのじゃ
Makeup art was there too.
ームーブフェスもあったのじゃ
Move Fes was there too.
防犯カメラ作動中もあったのじゃ
Security camera in operation was there too.
部屋も3つ。従業員専用、清掃員詰所
Three rooms too. Staff only, janitor's room.
消火栓
Fire hydrant.
いけるのじゃ
I can do it.
禁煙
No smoking.
左側通行
Keep left.
あれ、なんか変なのある
Huh, there's something weird.
ね、これ前なかったのじゃ
Hey, this wasn't here before.
ね、0って書いてるよ
Hey, it says 0.
0番になってるのじゃ
It's become number 0.
異変を見逃さないこと。異変を見つけたら、すぐに引き返すこと
Do not overlook any anomalies. If you find anomalies, turn back immediately.
異変が見つからなかったら、引き返さないこと
If you don't find anomalies, do not turn back.
これが出発？これがスタートなのじゃ？
Is this departure? Is this the start?
のじゃ、サンプルなのじゃ？
Huh, is this a sample?
見逃した？見逃したの？気付かなかったのじゃ
I missed it? I missed it? I didn't notice it.
0番、南武公園、水清中学校、米子寺、成平ビル、八本木交差点
Number 0, Nanbu Park, Mizuse Junior High School, Yonago Temple, Narihira Bldg, Happongi Crossing.
よし、行きますのじゃ。わしの始めるのじゃ
Alright, let's go. I'm starting.
なんかこのね、閉鎖空間がね、怖いんじゃよ
Somehow, this enclosed space is scary.
あ、おじさん
Ah, the old man.
禁煙ノーマモーキング、出口8あるのじゃ
No smoking, Exit 8 is there.
おじさんも通ってる。エイト歯科医院、8月8日オープン
The old man is walking too. Eight Dental Clinic, opening August 8th.
木日休み、アルバイト
Closed Thu/Sun, part-time job.
アルバイトOK、分電盤室
Part-time job OK, electrical room.
おじさん？...
Old man? ...
引き返...ん、何に？
Turn ba... hm, for what?
目が怖い？わし見れてない
The eyes are scary? I couldn't see them.
これ進んだら怒られる？これ進んだら怒られるのじゃ？
Will I get scolded if I go forward? Will I get scolded if I go forward?
いったん進んでみるのじゃ
Let's try going forward for a bit.
0になった！
It became 0!
ね、0になった
Hey, it became 0.
間違ってってことなのはじゃ？0だったらダメってことって聞いた
Does that mean I messed up? I heard if it's 0, it's bad.
もっかいやるのじゃ
Let's do it again.
ちょコメント欄見ないように頑張るのじゃ
I'll try hard not to look at the comment section.
一人で頑張ってみますのじゃいったん。8ね？
I'll try my best alone for now. 8, right?
よしよしよしよしよしよしよし、8ね？ちょおじさん、まずおじさんの顔見る
Alright alright alright, 8 right? Wait, old man, first let me look at the old man's face.
ために止まるのじゃ。止まってみるのじゃ。
Let's stop for this. Let's try stopping.
ゆっくりとね。うん。
Slowly, right? Yeah.
時間制限ないじゃろ?
There's no time limit, right?
おじさん見せて顔。おじさん真顔。
Mister, show me your face. Mister, straight face.
おじさん真顔じゃからいいんじゃない?
Mister's face is straight, so that's fine, right?
これワシでスタックしたらこれも異変になる?
If I stack this, will this also be an anomaly?
これもまただめ?
Is this also no good?
エイト歯科医院。
Eight Dental Clinic.
木日休みなのじゃ。
Closed on Thursdays and Sundays.
時給1000円。10-18、18-22。
Hourly wage 1,000 yen. 10 to 18, 18 to 22.
よくあるやつ。
A common one.
分電盤室。ドッグサロンZUI。
Electrical distribution room. Dog Salon ZUI.
司法書士。ドッグサロン司法書士?
Judicial scrivener. Dog Salon Judicial Scrivener?
監視カメラもあるのじゃ。
There's also a security camera.
えっとメイクアップ、ムーヴフェス。
Um, Makeup, Move Fest.
これ変わんないのじゃセキュリティカメラインオペレーション。
This doesn't change. Security camera in operation.
従業員専用、日乃用人。
Employee only, Hino Youjin.
よしよしよしよしよしよし。
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
これ異変ない気がするのじゃ。ワシ的に。
I feel like there's no anomaly here. Personally.
左側通行。
Keep left.
えっ、またゼロ!
Eh, zero again!
またゼロなのじゃ!なんか新しい!
It's zero again! Something's new!
なんか新しい!ええーっ!
Something's new! Eeh!
覚えゲーってむずいのじゃ。
Memory games are hard.
はいおじさん来る!出口8!
Okay, mister's coming! Exit 8!
ちょ頑張って覚えるのじゃ。
Let's do our best to memorize.
20回やったら覚えるのじゃさすがに。ノースモーキング。
If I do it 20 times, I'll memorize it. No Smoking.
出口8ちょおじさんの顔もゆっくり見るのじゃ。
Exit 8. Let's also look slowly at the mister's face.
え、エイト歯科医院。
Uh, Eight Dental Clinic.
おじさんの顔!おじさんの顔オッケー。
Mister's face! Mister's face is okay.
天井というかも見るのじゃ。
Ceiling, or rather, let's look at the ceiling too.
えっとのじゃ、エイト歯科医院バイト募集。
Um, let's see, Eight Dental Clinic part-time job recruitment.
天井天井天井。床床床。
Ceiling, ceiling, ceiling. Floor, floor, floor.
床も特に何もない。
Nothing particular on the floor either.
アルバイト、ZUI、司法書士。
Part-time job, ZUI, Judicial scrivener.
メイクアップ、ムーヴフェスでお部屋が分電盤室。
Makeup, Move Fest. And the room is electrical distribution room.
従業員専用清掃員詰所。消火栓。
Employee only, cleaner's room. Fire hydrant.
振り返る!地下広場!
Turn around! Underground plaza!
地下広場がこちら。
The underground plaza is over here.
地下広場じゃだめ?
Is the underground plaza no good?
地下広場に偽物?
A fake in the underground plaza?
一旦これでいってみますのじゃ。
Let's try going with this for once.
左側通行ですのじゃ。
It's keep left.
あっ、ねえ見て!ねえお前ら見て!
Ah, hey look! Hey everyone look!
お前ら見て数字が!数字が1になった!
Hey everyone look, the numbers! The numbers became 1!
今までずっと0だったのに!すごいのだじゃ!
Even though it was always 0 until now! That's amazing!
これ進めたってこと?先ほどまでがだめだったけど今回は進めたってことなのじゃ?
Does that mean I advanced? The previous ones were no good, but does that mean I advanced this time?
やったあ!やったやったやった!
Yay! Yay, yay, yay!
これクリアと言っても過言ではないのじゃ!
It's no exaggeration to call this cleared!
もうクリアしたと言っても過言ではない。このゲームの攻略法を見つけたのじゃ。
It's no exaggeration to say I've cleared it. I found the walkthrough for this game.
よしよしよしよしこのまま行くのじゃ。この調子ですのじゃ。
Okay, okay, okay, let's keep going like this. Let's keep this up.
異変全部見つけるのじゃ!
Find all the anomalies!
全然怖くないじゃん。全然怖くないのじゃ。
It's not scary at all. It's not scary at all.
よしこれぐらいならいけるのじゃ。出口8禁煙ノースモーキング。
Okay, if it's about this much, I can do it. Exit 8, No Smoking.
ちょおじさんの顔をゆっくり見たいから待っててあげよう。待っててあげよう。
I want to look slowly at the mister's face, so let's wait for him. Let's wait for him.
おじさん、顔見せて。
Mister, show me your face.
普通の顔。普通の顔。
Normal face. Normal face.
エイト歯科医院。
Eight Dental Clinic.
オッケーのじゃ。
Okay.
アルバイト、オッケーなのじゃ。
Part-time job, okay.
ドッグサロンZUIオッケーなのじゃ。
Dog Salon ZUI, okay.
分電盤室オッケーなのじゃ。
Electrical distribution room, okay.
司法書士もあったし、メイクアートもあったし、監視カメラもあるし、
There was the judicial scrivener, makeup art, security camera,
従業員専用もあるし、
Employee only area,
ムーヴフェスもあるし、防犯カメラもあるのじゃ。
Move Fest, and a security camera.
清掃員詰所もある。
Cleaner's room as well.
消火栓もある。日の用人じゃ。後ろを向く。
Fire hydrant too. Hino Youjin. Turn around.
引き返せだって!ねえ見てお前ら!お前ら危ないって!
Turn back! Hey look everyone! Hey everyone, it's dangerous!
お前らお前らお前ら、ワシ見つけたよ!ワシ見つけたのじゃ!
Everyone, everyone, everyone, I found it! I found it!
異変見つけたのじゃ!異変なのだじゃ異変なのだじゃ!
I found the anomaly! It's an anomaly, it's an anomaly!
引き返せって書いてる。ワシわかる。
It says turn back. I know.
引き返すのじゃ。あっ、後ずさり。
Turn back. Ah, backing away.
追いかけられたらやだからね。後ずさり。後ずさり。
Because I don't want to be chased. Backing away. Backing away.
教えてくれるの優しいのじゃ。教えてくれるの優しい。
It's kind of it to tell me. It's kind to tell me.
え、何?おじさんがいる。
Eh, what? There's a mister.
どうしたのじゃ?おじさん……
What's wrong, mister? Mister...
何？ スマホ見ている。
What? Is he looking at his phone?
何？ これ怖い？
What? Is this scary?
これ怖いやつ？
Is this a scary one?
真ん中で立ち止まりスマホはね、ダメって聞いたことがあるのじゃ。
I heard stopping in the middle of the hallway is bad...
しかも展示ブロックの上、炎上しちゃうのじゃおじさん。
And on a display block! You'll catch fire, old man!
おじさん展示ブロックの上で止まったらね、今の時代じゃね、炎上しちゃうから危ないのじゃ。
If you stop on a display block in this day and age, you'll catch fire, so be careful.
馬鹿野郎じゃあ。
Idiot old man.
に、あ、2になった！
Two? Ah, it became two!
2になったのじゃ、2になったのじゃ！2、2だよ、2！
It became two, it became two, it's two, it's two!
1の次！
Next after one!
いけるのじゃ。
We can do it, right?
この調子で、え、怖くないのじゃ？怖くないのじゃ？
With this mood, isn't it scary? Isn't it scary?
監視カメラ。
Security camera.
え、わしホラゲいけるかも！
Wait, I might be able to go to Holalg!
わしホラゲの神になる可能性あり。おじさん。
There's a chance I could become a Holalg god! Old man!
よし。しかと見させていただきますのじゃ。
Okay, let me watch you, old man.
禁煙、オッケー？禁煙、オッケー？
No smoking, okay? No smoking, okay?
おじさん、オッケー？おじさん、オッケー？
Old man, okay? Old man, okay?
うん。おじさん。うん。
Old man. Old man.
おじさんのお顔を見してほしいのじゃ。普通のお顔なのじゃ。
I want you to show me the old man's face. It's a normal face!
オープン、オープン、オープンじゃ。
Open, open, open!
アルバイトのじゃ？アルバイトのじゃ？
Part-time job? Part-time job?
分電盤室のじゃ？
Switchboard room?
ドッグ、ドッグズイ？
Dog Zui?
司法書士？
Judicial scrivener?
メイクアップアートのじゃ？
Makeup art?
ムーヴフェス！
Move Fes!
従業員専用、清掃員詰所、消化線。
Employee-only, cleaning supplies, fire extinguishing line.
防犯カメラ作動中！セキュリティカメラ。
Security camera in operation! Security camera!
わ、カメラここにある！
Oh, there's a camera here!
ある。地下広場！
There is one. Basement plaza!
え、何もない！何もない！異変なし！
Eh? There's nothing! There's nothing! No anomaly!
異変なし。チェックして、問題なし！
No anomaly! Check, and no problem!
あ、でも一応振り返るのか。振り返り。
Oh, but I have to turn back once, right? Turning back.
異変なし。
No anomaly!
なしですのじゃ。進むのじゃー！
There is none, let's keep going!
え、これもうRTAなんじゃないの？
Hey, isn't this RTA?
さんだ！ねえ、さん、さん！さんなのじゃ、さんなのじゃ！
Three! Hey, three, three! It's three! It's three!
ねえ、3、3になってる！3になってるということは正解ってこと！
Hey, it became three! Since it became three, that means it's correct!
おおお！
Whoa!
わしのプレイスキルに、お主らきっと今恐怖を慄いてるんじゃないの？
Doesn't this mean my free skill is actually terrifying?!
なかなかの、なかなかの記憶力なのじゃ。うわ、謝罪しなくてよかったなこれ。
What a great memory! Wow, I didn't even need to apologize for this!
これ謝罪しなくてよかったかもなのじゃ。
I might not have needed to apologize, you know?
冒頭に謝罪いらなかったのじゃ。のじゃ、行くのじゃ。
I didn't need to apologize at the beginning, you know? Let's go!
出口8。
Exit 8.
おじさんのこと見ててあげる。
Let's watch out for the old man.
禁煙ノースモーキングオッケー？
No smoking, okay?
エイト歯科医院オッケー？
Eight dental clinic, okay?
おじさんお顔を見して、おじさん。
Show me the old man's face, old man.
おじさん普通なのじゃ。変わり映えしない日々。わしとおじさん。
The old man is normal! Days with no surprises, just me and the old man.
オープン、アルバイト大募集オッケー？
Open, part-time job wanted, okay?
分電盤室オッケー？
Switchboard room, okay?
ズイオッケー？
Zui, okay?
司法書士オッケー？
Judicial scrivener, okay?
メイクアップアートオッケー？
Makeup art, okay?
え、異変なくてわろた。従業員専用、清掃員詰所。
No anomaly, employee-only, cleaning supplies, and...
え、ねえ目動いてる！目動いてる！め、め、め、め、め、目動いてるのじゃ！
Wait, the eyes are moving! The eyes are moving! The eyes are moving, no way!
え、これ異変、これ異変です！これ異変ですのじゃ！これ絶対に異変ですのじゃ！えー、何？
Wait, this is an anomaly, this is definitely an anomaly! What?
ハイテクな広告！ハイテクな広告！
Hi-tech advertisement? Hi-tech advertisement?
わしも出したい！ねえ、わしも、わしも目動く広告出したい！
I want to put out an ad too! I want my eyes to move in an ad!
わしも動く広告出したいのじゃ。あ、秋葉原駅で、秋葉原駅で今遊び回りたいの、動く広告が出てますのじゃ。
I want to put out a moving ad too! At Akihabara Station, I want to hang out at Akihabara Station now—wait, a moving ad is out, you know?
4。
Four?
え、あってっぽいい。あってっぽいい。
Eh, seems correct. Seems correct.
え、すごくない？わしすごい、わしすごい！ね、わしすごいよ！ね、わしすごい！
Eh, isn't it amazing? I'm amazing, I'm amazing! I'm really amazing! I'm really amazing!
順調すぎて、わろた。順調じゃん。
Things are going too well, so I laughed. Everything is going great!
これいけるのじゃ。
I can do this, right?
ごめんお主ら。今日お主らと長い時間一緒に配信で過ごしたかったお主らガチごめんなのじゃ。これ病ですのじゃ。
Sorry, old man. I really wanted to stream with you for a long time today, old man, I'm seriously sorry, you know? This is fatal, you know?
記憶力の神こと、わし、アチチメラ！
The absolute god of memory, myself, Achchimera!
え、謝罪しなきゃよかったのじゃ。
I should have apologized, you know?
危なかったら走るのをやった方がいい？あ、走るとかもあるのじゃ？理解なのだ。
If it's not safe, should I run? Ah, running is also an option, you know? Got it.
で、出口8。
So, Exit 8.
禁煙、ノー・スモーキング？
No smoking?
エイト歯科？エイト歯科？
Eight Dental? Eight Dental?
アルバイト？おじさん？オッケー？
Part-time job? Old man? Okay?
おじさんオッケー？おじさんオッケー？
Old man okay? Old man okay?
分電盤室オッケー？出口8オッケー？
Electrical room okay? Exit 8 okay?
アルバイトオッケー？
Part-time job okay?
ドッグサロン・ズイオッケー？
Dog Salon Zui okay?
ええ、司法書士オッケー？
Um, judicial scrivener okay?
んーと、メイクアップ・アーティストオッケー？
Um, makeup artist okay?
ムーブフェス？
Move Fes?
あ、ねえ、動かない広告、安心感ありますのじゃ！
Static ads give me a sense of security!
安心感ある。
A sense of security.
防犯カメラ作動中、防犯カメラある、防犯カメラもある、従業員専用ある、ある、清掃員詰所ある。
Security cameras, staff room, cleaning office.
え？なくないへん？
Huh? Isn't there something weird?
消火栓、火の用心じゃ？
Fire hydrant, watch out for fire?
火の用心じゃ？
Watch out for fire?
異変ないのじゃ？異変ないのじゃ？
No anomaly? No anomaly?
え、異変ないのじゃ？
Huh, no anomaly?
行くのじゃー！いけるのじゃいけるのじゃいけるのじゃー！
Let's go! We can do this!
5ー！え、5だよ、5！5じゃよ、5！5じゃよ、5ってことは5ってことなのじゃ！
5! Huh, it's 5! 5 means it's 5!
あと3つじゃ！
Three left!
え、え、え？秒で終わるのじゃ？秒で終わるのじゃ？
Huh, it ends in a second?
わし、わしすごい。わしすごいかも。わし、これからホラーゲーマーになろうかな。わし、これから間違い探し記憶力系ホラーゲーマーになろうかな。
I'm amazing. Should I become a horror gamer?
わし、これで派遣取るのじゃ。
I'll get a temporary placement with this.
あちチメラと 言えば、あちちメラの代名詞、ホラーゲーム、謎、謎探し系のホラーゲーマー。
Speaking of Achichi Mera, puzzle horror gamer.
うわ、すごいのだ。わしの新しい一面が主らにちら。
Whoa, a new side of me peeking out.
おじさん来た。
Old man is here.
禁煙、ノー・スモーキングオッケー？
No smoking, no smoking okay?
ノー・スモーキングオッケー？
No smoking okay?
出口8オッケー？
Exit 8 okay?
おじさん見るのじゃ、おじさん。
Look at the old man.
おじさんオッケー？
Old man okay?
普通の顔。
Normal face.
後ろ姿も普通。
Back view is also normal.
えーっと、エイト歯科医院オッケー？
Um, Eight Dental Clinic okay?
木日休み？アルバイトオッケー？
Closed Thursday and Sunday? Part-time job okay?
8番出口、分電盤室。
Exit 8, electrical room.
ドッグサロン・ズイ、ズイ。
Dog Salon Zui, Zui.
司法書士、司法書士。
Judicial scrivener, judicial scrivener.
ええと、メイクアップ・アートオッケー？ムーブフェスオッケー？
Makeup art okay? Move Fes okay?
従業員専用、聖しょ、え、なくない？ないのじゃ？
Staff only, wait, isn't it missing?
防犯カメラ作動中。
Security camera in operation.
防犯カメラもある！地下広場。
There's a security camera! Underground plaza.
え、異変ないのじゃ？
Huh, no anomaly?
異変ねえのじゃ？何なのじゃ？このゲーム、のじゃ？
No anomaly? What is this game?
ない。ないよ、ないのじゃ。
None. None, it's not there.
進むのじゃ。後ろ見る。
Keep going. Look behind.
ないのじゃ。ない！
It's not there. None!
うわ！見て、666！6なのだじゃー！
Whoa! Look, 666! It's 6!
6なのだじゃね、異変なさすぎじゃない？
It's 6, isn't there way too little anomaly?
全然異変ないのじゃ。なんで？わしがごりおく担当だから？ごりおく担当なわしの為にしてくれてるのじゃ？だってじゃないのじゃ！
Because I'm in charge of divine favor? No way!
RTA勢として立候補させていただきますのじゃ！RTA勢として立候補させていただきますのじゃ！
I'd like to run as an RTA runner!
よいしょ、進むのじゃ。
Heave-ho, keep going.
え、早いね？ここわいこわいこわいこわいこわい！
Huh, fast? This is so scary!
早いのだ！
It's fast!
なんか早い！何？のじゃ？
Somehow fast! What? Huh?
なんか早くなかった？え？なに？
Wasn't it fast? Huh? What?
っ、なに？
Eh, what?
早かった。なんか、早かったのじゃ。
It was fast. Somehow, it was fast.
何？え、あ、あの、あの人さ、あの おじさんさ、あの おじさんさ、速すぎでさ、多分さ、多分さ、わしがさ、のんびりさ、のんびり行ってたらさ、さ、のんびり行ってたら多分捕まってたのじゃのじゃ。
That old man was so fast, if I'd been leisurely...
のじゃ、す、進むのじゃ。7番デス之じゃ。怖い之じゃ。
Keep going. It's Exit 7. It's scary.
はあー、ゆっくりのおじさんだ。ゆっくりのおじさんだ。
Phew, it's a slow old man.
おっさんじゃん？
It's a middle-aged man, huh?
さっきの問題よりずっと早いのやつ、あんまり良くないネタだったっぽいのだじゃ。
The one that appeared much faster than before... seems like not a very good bit, huh.
ちょっとちょっと切ないネタだったっぽいのだじゃ。ちゃんと調べ直したのじゃ、元のネタ。
It seemed like a somewhat sad bit, huh. I looked it up properly, the original reference.
おじさん？ 普通のおじさん？
An uncle? A normal uncle?
背中も普通？背中も普通のおじさん？背中の普通のおじさん？
Is his back normal too? A normal uncle's back? A normal uncle's back?
エイト歯科オッケー？ エイト歯科オッケー？
Eight Dental is OK? Eight Dental is OK?
アルバイトパートオッケー？
Part-time job recruitment is OK?
順番頑張って覚えてるのに順番全部同じなのだじゃ。ズイオッケー？
I'm trying hard to remember the order, but the order is all the same. Zui is OK?
分電盤室オッケー？ 司法書士オッケー？ メイクアップアートオッケー？ ムーブフェスオッケー？
Electrical room OK? Judicial scrivener OK? Makeup art OK? Move Fes OK?
防犯カメラオッケー？
Security camera OK?
従業員通路？従業員専用？地下広場？へえ、変なのじゃ。
Employee hallway? Employee only? Underground plaza? Huh, how weird.
防犯カメラもある。
There's a security camera too.
変なのじゃ。消火栓もあるのじゃ。変なのじゃ。
How weird. There's a fire hydrant too. How weird.
もうじゃ、進むのじゃ。
Well then, I'll keep going.
ゼロ？
Zero?
なんでゼロ？ ん？
Why zero? Hm?
のじゃ？ なんでゼロだったの？
Huh? Why was it zero?
なんでゼロだったの？何が、何が変だったのじゃ？
Why was it zero? What, what was weird about it?
え、なかった！変ない、変ないのじゃ！変形がないのじゃ！え、変ないのに、のじゃ？ のじゃ？
Eh, there was none! There's no anomaly! There's no abnormality! Eh, even though there's no anomaly, huh? Huh?
もう1回しっかり見てみますのじゃ。でもやることは分かったのじゃ。
I'll take a close look again. But I figured out what to do.
やることは分かったのじゃ。
I figured out what to do.
戻って見れるの？戻って見れるらしい。戻って見るのじゃ。
Can I go back and check? Apparently I can go back and check. I'll go back and look.
ダッシュできない。あれ？ ダッシュできない異変ですのじゃ。
I can't dash. Huh? An anomaly where I can't dash, huh.
のじゃのじゃのじゃのじゃ、のじゃのじゃのじゃのじゃ。
Noja noja noja noja, noja noja noja noja.
のじゃ？ あ、戻れなっぽい。もっかい頑張り回すのじゃ。
Huh? Ah, looks like I can't go back. I'll try spinning around again.
エイト歯科医院、アルバイト募集、分電盤室。
Eight Dental Clinic, Part-time job hiring, Electrical room.
オープン、ドッグオープン。
Open, Dog Open.
おじさんオッケー？ おじさん、大丈夫？ うん、大丈夫。
Uncle OK? Uncle, are you okay? Yeah, you're okay.
司法書士オッケー？ メイクアップアートオッケー？ ムーブフェスオッケー？ 防犯カメラ？ 防犯カメラも回りますのじゃ。地下広場。
Judicial scrivener OK? Makeup art OK? Move Fes OK? Security camera? The security camera rotates too. Underground plaza.
うんうんうん。従業員専用。清掃員詰所。
Mhm mhm mhm. Employee only. Cleaner's office.
よし！ 何？何？何？やめて！おじさんのじゃ！何？暗い暗い暗い！な、行き止まり！
Alright! What? What? What? Stop! It's the uncle! What? It's dark, dark, dark! A dead end!
な、ちょ、中落とす、落とす、落とす！
Wait, drop it, drop it, drop it!
何？ 何？ 何？
What? What? What?
のじゃ？ のじゃ？ な、なんで消えた？
Noja? Noja? Wh-why did it disappear?
何？ な、ま、なん、なん、なんで電気消えたのじゃ？
What? Wh-wh-wh-why did the lights go out?
え、で、電気消えるの異変？ え？ え？ い、い、今のわ、今のわそういう異変？ 今のはそういう異変なのじゃ？
Eh, lights going out is an anomaly? Eh? Eh? Is that, is that kind of anomaly? Was that that kind of anomaly?
はー、心落ち着くのじゃ。心落ち着くのじゃ。心落ち着くのじゃ。
Hah... Calming my heart. Calming my heart. Calming my heart.
よしよしよし。心落ち着くのじゃ。びっくりしたのじゃ。びっくりしたのじゃ。びっくりしたのじゃ。
There, there, there. Calming my heart. I was so startled. I was so startled. I was so startled.
はあ、心落ち着くのじゃ。心落ち着くのじゃ。なに？
Haah, calming my heart. Calming my heart. What?
心落ち着くのじゃ。心落ち着くのじゃ。なんだのじゃ？ ああ、びっくりしたのじゃ。
Calming my heart. Calming my heart. What was that? Ah, I was so startled.
なんか、のじゃ。のじゃ。のじゃ。
Something... noja. Noja. Noja.
地下のお水も、お水も飲むのじゃ。お水もお水も飲むのじゃ。
Drinking the underground water too. Drinking water, drinking water.
びっくりしたのじゃ。びっくりしたのじゃ。
I was so startled. I was so startled.
のじゃ。びっくりしたのじゃ。びっくりしたのじゃ。のじゃあ。
Noja. I was so startled. I was so startled. Nojaaa.
のじゃ。のじゃ。のじゃ。
Noja. Noja. Noja.
うん。異変でしたのじゃ。異変でしたのじゃ。
Yeah. That was an anomaly. That was an anomaly.
怖いのじゃ。でも、でも頑張って引き返せたのじゃ。
It's scary. But, but I managed to turn back.
おっ、待て。聞き返しちゃうのじゃ。
Wait, let me check the playback.
わし、ちょっとホラゲ派遣無理かもなのじゃ。
I might not be cut out for horror games.
ホラゲ系YouTuberを
I was aiming to be a horror VTuber...
ホラーライブホラゲ担当を目指していたんじゃが。
aiming to be in charge of horror live streams.
ホラーライブホラゲ部門1Vチューバーを目指していたんじゃが。
Aiming to be the top horror VTuber...
ちょっと、わしには、わしには無理そうですのじゃ。
Well, it seems it might be too much for me.
今まで、今までありがとうございましたのじゃ。
Thank you for everything up until now.
ちょっと、ちょっとびっくり系は難しいですのじゃ。
Jump scares are just too difficult for me.
ちょっと、ちょっと中々、
It's pretty... pretty tough.
大変ですのじゃ。
It's really tough.
呼吸の吸い過ぎで体が痺れておりますのじゃ。
My body is getting numb from breathing too much.
ちょっと心拍数計貸してほしいのじゃ。
Someone please lend me a heart rate monitor.
今やばいのじゃ。100、100、200になるのじゃ。
It's dangerous right now. 100, 100, 200.
無理なのはじゃ。
It's impossible.
ちょっと一旦使わせていただいてよろしいですのじゃ。
May I use it for just a moment?
ちょっと一旦、一旦ね。
Just for a moment...
うう、怖かった！怖かったのじゃ！
Ugh, that was scary! So scary!
びっくり系はアズルなのじゃ。
Jump scares are unfair.
あんまり驚かせないでほしいのじゃ。
Please don't surprise me too much.
よし！行くのじゃ！
Alright! Here I go!
全部倒す！全部倒す！全部倒す！全部倒すのじゃ！
I'll defeat them all! Defeat them all!
えっとなんかノーモーキングオッケー？
Um, no smoking, okay?
えっとなんか看板ロックオッケー？
Exit sign lock, okay?
えっとなんか視界インオッケー？
Field of view, okay?
おじさんも見るのじゃ？アルバイトパートナー大募集オッケー？
Check the old man too? Part-time job recruitment, okay?
ドッグラン、ドッグサロン、おじさんの顔オッケーなのじゃ。
Dog run, dog salon, the old man's face is okay.
背中もオッケーなのじゃ。分電盤室オッケー？
His back is okay too. Distribution board room, okay?
司法書士オッケー？
Judicial scrivener, okay?
えっメイクアップオッケー？MOVEFESオッケー？
Makeup, okay? MOVEFES, okay?
防犯カメラオッケー。防犯カメラもあるのじゃ。
Security camera, okay. There's also a security camera.
そして従業員専用、どう見ても異様じゃないのじゃ。
And employee-only... doesn't it look abnormal?
清掃員もおかしくないのじゃ。
The cleaner isn't weird either.
地下広場、うむ。
Underground plaza, hmm.
床にも天井にも異変はないんじゃなかろうか。
Could there be no anomalies on the floor or ceiling?
ああ、やっぱびっくりさせる系って良くないのじゃ。
Ah, surprise elements really aren't good.
心臓に悪いですのじゃ。
It's bad for the heart.
うう、怖かったあ！怖かったあ！
Ugh, that was so scary! So scary!
え、ゼロ？
Eh, zero?
ゼロなのじゃ。
It's zero.
なんて？見たい？見たい？
What? Want to see? Want to see?
今何が異変だったの？今何が異変じゃったの？
What was the anomaly just now? What was it?
ないよ。
There isn't any.
異変ないのじゃ。
There's no anomaly.
台所？
Kitchen?
天井？
Ceiling?
どこ？
Where?
うわ！ありありありあり！
Whoa! There is, there is, there is!
え、何？これ？
Eh, what? This?
何？何？これ？何？
What? What is this? What?
し、し、しみ？
A... a stain?
ええ？
Eh?
怖ーい！
Scary!
またゼロからなのじゃ。
Back to zero again.
よし、ゼロから頑張るのじゃ！
Alright, I'll do my best from zero!
わし、プレイ中はね、コメント欄見てないから。
I don't look at the comment section while playing.
プレイ中はコメント欄見てないから大丈夫なのじゃ。
So it's completely fine.
振り返りの時だけ見ているのじゃ。
I only look during reviews.
行くのじゃ！
Here I go!
なんかさ、地味な異変ちょっとズルなのだ。
Subtle anomalies are kind of unfair.
ちょ地味だから気づきづらいのじゃ。
They're subtle so it's hard to notice.
禁煙オッケー、ノースモーキングオッケー。
No smoking okay, no smoking okay.
えっ視界インオッケー？
Field of view, okay?
えっ看板オッケー？
Sign, okay?
えっパートオッケー？おじさんの顔も見ますのじゃ。
Part-time okay? I'll check the old man's face too.
おじさんの顔も普通なのじゃ。
The old man's face is normal too.
普通、スマホ持ってる。
Normal, holding a smartphone.
背中もオッケーですのじゃ。うむ。
His back is okay too. Hmm.
分電盤室オッケー？
Distribution board room, okay?
えっオープンオッケー、司法書士オッケー。
Open okay, judicial scrivener okay.
メイクアップオッケー。
Makeup, okay.
MOVEFESオッケー。
MOVEFES, okay.
防犯カメラオッケー。
Security camera, okay.
分電盤室。
Distribution board room.
従業員専用。
Employee only.
従業員専用。従業員専用。
Employee only. Employee only.
清掃員詰所、防犯カメラ。
Cleaner's room, security camera.
よーし、行くのじゃ！
Alright, here I go!
え、このゲーム難しくない？
Eh, isn't this game hard?
何が違ったんじゃ？何が違ったんじゃ？
What was different? What was different?
ちょ振り返り、振り返り、振り返り、教えて教えて。
Hold on, review, review, review! Tell me, tell me!
振り返りターンなのじゃ。
It's review turn, you know.
何が違った？
What was different?
おじさんがずっと見てた？
Was the old man staring the whole time?
なるほど、そういう異変もあるのじゃ。
I see, so that kind of anomaly exists too.
ちょっとパターンゲームなのじゃ。
It's kind of a pattern game.
パターンゲーム！
Pattern game!
パターンキー！パターンキーなのじゃ。
Pattern key! It's a pattern key, you know.
妖怪なのじゃ。
It's a yōkai, you know.
行くのじゃ。
Here I go.
え、もしかして最初めっちゃ運よかった？
Eh, could it be my luck was super good at first?
もしかしてめっちゃ最初運よかったのじゃ？
Could it be my luck was super good right at the start?
よし、行かせていただきますのじゃ。
Alright, I will humbly proceed.
ちょ、おじさんが見てるかど、じゃ、見てるか判断するためにおじさんからちょっと遠くにいなきゃいけないってことじゃろう、な。
To judge if the old man is watching, I need to be far from him, right?
禁煙の、スモーキングオッケー？
No smoking, smoking okay?
エイト歯科オッケー？
Eighth Dental Clinic okay?
アルバイトオッケー？
Part-time job okay?
おじさん見る？
Old man, let's see.
お主を見とおる。
The master is watching you.
The master is watching.
む、異変なし！
Hm, no anomaly!
異変なし！
No anomaly!
分電盤室オッケー？
Distribution board room okay?
うん。ドッグサロンオッケー？
Yeah. Dog salon okay?
司法書士オッケー？
Judicial scrivener okay?
メイクアップアートオッケー？
Makeup art okay?
ムーブフェスオッケー？
Move Fes okay?
防犯カメラもオッケー？
Security camera also okay?
そして従業員専用、詰め所。
And employee-only, staff room.
消火栓オッケー！
Fire hydrant okay!
うん、地下広場。
Yeah, underground plaza.
異変なし！
No anomaly!
これでやったら切れるのじゃ！
If I do it like this, it cuts off!
切れてみせるのじゃ。
I'll show you it cuts off.
ふー、やっと1！
Whew, finally 1!
やっと進めたのじゃ！
I finally advanced!
ちょっとこのままご利益パワーで、ご利益パワーで行きたいのじゃ。1。よし、行きますのじゃ。
Let's go with this blessing power. 1. Alright, here I go.
分かってきたのじゃ。ゲーム理解丸。
I'm starting to understand. Game understanding: circle.
ゲーム理解20丸。
Game understanding: double circle.
はい、出口8オッケー。
Right, exit 8 okay.
禁煙オッケー。
No smoking okay.
6個看板ある。
There are 6 signboards.
8月8エイト歯科。
August 8th Eighth Dental.
えー、アルバイトパート。
Uh, part-time job.
おじさん普通の顔、わしのこともう見ていない、後ろ姿オッケー？
Old man normal face, not looking at me, back view okay?
分電盤室オッケー？
Distribution board room okay?
ZUI司法書士。
ZUI Judicial Scrivener.
メイクアップアート。
Makeup art.
ムーブフェス。
Move Fes.
防犯カメラ？
Security camera?
そして従業員専用、清掃員、清掃員詰め所。
And employee-only, cleaner's staff room.
地下広場！
Underground plaza!
消火栓オッケー。
Fire hydrant okay.
後ろ見る。
Look behind.
オッケーなのじゃ。進む。
It's okay. Proceed.
進む。
Proceed.
2、2、2、2ネスのじゃ。
2, 2, 2, business, you know!
もう勝ったのじゃ。1回掴んでしまえば、1回掴んでしまえばもう勝ったも同然。
I've already won. Once you grasp it, it's practically a win.
出口にゆきますのじゃ。
I will go to the exit.
白。出口8、123456ある。
White. Exit 8, there are 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
123とびらある。
There are 1, 2, 3 doors.
えー、禁煙オッケー。
Uh, no smoking okay.
禁煙ノースモーキングオッケーのじゃ。
No smoking, non-smoking okay, you know.
そう、買ったのがははんこなのじゃ。
Right, winning is haha, you know.
おじさんちゃんと見るよ。おじさん？おじさんオッケー？
I'll look at the old man properly. Old man? Old man okay?
おじさんの後ろ姿も見るよ。おじさんの後ろ姿オッケーなのはじゃ！オッケーなのはじゃ！
I'll see his back too. The old man's back view is okay, you know!
よしよしよしよしよしよし。んでエイト歯科オッケー？
Alright, alright. And Eighth Dental Clinic okay?
パートオッケー？
Part-time job okay?
ZUIオッケー？分電盤室オッケー？
ZUI okay? Distribution board room okay?
司法書士オッケー？メイクアップアートオッケー？
Judicial scrivener okay? Makeup art okay?
ムーブフェスオッケーなのじゃ。んで
Move Fes is okay, you know. And
えーと、防犯カメラもオッケーなのはじゃ。従業員専用、清掃員清掃員。
Security camera okay. Employee-only, cleaner, cleaner.
地下広場、え、なくない？
Underground plaza, eh, isn't it missing?
ないのじゃ、ないのじゃ。
It's missing, it's missing.
消火栓、うん。
Fire hydrant, yeah.
後ろから見るのじゃ。あ、もう1回天井とかね。
Looking from behind. Ah, let's check the ceiling again.
でも天井も見たのじゃ。天井も見たのじゃ。
But I already checked the ceiling. I checked the ceiling too.
よし、行くのじゃ。
Alright, here I go.
大丈夫なのだじゃ。
It's okay, you know.
答え合わせ。
Check the answers.
なのじゃ。
You know.
え、0？0？
Eh, 0? 0?
なんて？なんでなんで？
Why, why, why?
なんて？なんでじゃ？ちょっとのじゃ。
What? Why? Wait a minute, you know.
何が違ったのじゃ？天井ブロックが釣…
What was different? The ceiling block is hanging...
はっ！本当だ！ね、天井ブロックがツルツル！ね、そんなのある！？そんなのなしなのじゃ！
Ha! The ceiling block is smooth! Is there such a thing?! That's unfair!
え、そんなのありなのじゃ？
Wait, is that even a thing?
わ、細かい
Wow, so detailed.
とても細かな、とても細かなのじゃ
So detailed, extremely detailed.
意味ねえのじゃ
Totally pointless.
天井ツルツル
Ceiling is smooth...
こういうのもあるのじゃ
They have things like this too.
なるほど、なるほど
I see, I see.
本当だ、こっからツルツルじゃなくなってる
Oh true, from here it's not smooth anymore.
ええ、なかなか面白いことを考えるのじゃ
Hmm, they come up with pretty interesting ideas.
見るとこいっぱいあるのじゃ
There's so much to look at.
ちょっと自分がゲーム製作者だったらどこにどういう異変を作りたいか考えながらやるのじゃ
If I were a game developer, I'd think about where and what kind of anomalies to make while playing.
難しいのじゃ
It's difficult.
これ出れる可能性、出れる可能性、いけるか？
Is it possible to escape? Can I make it?
いけますのじゃ、8
We can make it, 8.
ツルツルじゃない、禁煙、ノー・スモーキング
Not smooth, no smoking, no smoking.
エイト歯科、エイト歯科？
Eight Dental, Eight Dental?
アルバイト大募集、アルバイト大募集
Part-time job openings, part-time job openings.
ちょっと人間の顔をじっくり見させていただきますのじゃ
Let me take a close look at this person's face.
もしを見ている？もしを見ていない？
Are they looking? Are they not looking?
そして背中も大丈夫、カバンも持っているのじゃ
And their back is fine too, they're carrying a bag.
出口8
Exit 8.
アルバイト大募集
Part-time job openings.
分電盤室オッケー、分電盤室オッケー
Electrical room okay, electrical room okay.
エイト
Eight.
え、何これ？
Huh, what is this?
これ異変ですのじゃ、これ異変！
This is an anomaly, this is an anomaly!
もし異変見つけた、もし異変見つけた
I found an anomaly, I found an anomaly!
ねえ、怖い顔あった、怖い顔あった！
Hey, there was a scary face, there was a scary face!
怖い顔あった！
There was a scary face!
のじゃあ
Ah...
のじゃあ、びっくりした！
Ah, I was startled!
びっくりした！1
I was startled! 1.
恐ろしいのじゃ
That was terrifying.
そうか、こういうのも、こういうのも見なきゃいけない
Right, I have to check things like this too.
ノー・スモーキングオッケー
No smoking okay.
え、なんか階段？
Huh, is that stairs?
階段なのだじゃ
It's stairs.
明らかにおかしい
That's clearly strange.
階段、階段なのじゃ、階段、登っちゃダメじゃろ？
Stairs, it's stairs, stairs. You shouldn't go up, right?
え、ゴール？これゴール？これゴールなのじゃ？
Huh, goal? Is this the goal? Is this the goal?
え、でもまだまだ7回やってないよ？まだ7回やってないのじゃ？
Eh, but I haven't done 7 times yet? I haven't done 7 times yet?
え、7回やってないから異変なのじゃ？
Eh, since I haven't done 7 times, is it an anomaly?
ねえ、7回やってない、異変なのじゃ！
Hey, I haven't done 7 times, it's an anomaly!
だって、だって7、7と8、7と8、7と8じゃろ？7と8じゃろ？7と8、7と...
Because, because 7, 7 and 8, 7 and 8, 7 and 8, right? 7 and 8, right? 7 and 8, 7 and...
え、出られる？本当？本当？どっち？
Huh, can I get out? Really? Really? Which way?
ちょ、ちょコメント見ちゃ
Hold on, let me check the comments...
出るのじゃ！
Let's get out!
え、だってまだ、まだ1じゃしね？まだ1じゃしね？まだ1じゃしね？あ、0
Eh, because it's still 1, right? Still 1, right? Still 1, right? Ah, 0.
あ、0
Ah, 0.
何もないかい
Nothing there.
え、でも、でもまだ最初だったから
Eh, but, but it was still just the beginning.
まだ1じゃったから、まだ1じゃったからそんな、そんななのじゃ
It was still 1, so it was still just...
ちょっとおじさんチェックするのじゃ。おじさん失礼しますのじゃ。
Let's check the guy. Excuse me, sir.
傷の浅いうちにね、傷の浅いうちにね。
While the damage is still light, while the damage is still light.
はい、8月8日オープンなのじゃ。
Yes, opening on August 8th.
アルバイト募集なのじゃ。
Part-time job recruitment.
オープンニューズイのじゃ。
Open New Zui.
分電盤室のじゃ。
Electrical room.
えっと
Um...
日々の身近なトラブルも司法書士にお任せを
Leave your everyday troubles to a judicial scrivener.
メイクアップ、123456
Makeup, 1 2 3 4 5 6.
防犯カメラ
Security camera.
地下広場
Underground plaza.
地下広場、従業員専用、清掃員室、消火栓、ない
Underground plaza, staff only, janitor's room, fire hydrant, none.
異変ないのじゃ。
No anomalies.
異変ないのじゃ、進む。
No anomalies, moving forward.
もう1回振り返る、異変なし。
Looking back once more, no anomalies.
進むのじゃ。
Moving forward.
1、はい、戻ってきた！はい、戻ってきたのじゃ！
1, yes, I'm back! Yes, I'm back!
だからさっき階段の上登ったのはね、しょうがない、いいことなのじゃ。別になんかここで取り返せばいいから、あの、ここで取り返せばいいから、あの、大丈だからなのじゃ。
So going up the stairs earlier was, oh well, it's fine. It doesn't matter, we can just make up for it here, so it's okay.
いくのじゃ、8。
Let's go, 8.
禁煙、ノー・スモーキング、123456。
No smoking, no smoking, 1 2 3 4 5 6.
え、なんか出てる！なんか出てる！なんかドロドロ出てるのじゃ！
Eh, something's coming out! Something's coming out! Something sludge-like is coming out!
ねえ、右からドロドロ出てた。右からドロドロ出てた。右からドロドロ出てたのじゃ。
Hey, something was dripping from the right...
にー、にー、
Two, two...
はい、2に来ましたのじゃ。
Yes, we've come to exit 2.
よしよしよし、得意になってきた。
Alright, I'm getting good at this.
このゲーム全部理解した。分かってきたのじゃ。行くのじゃ。
I understand this game completely now. Let's go.
次は3。123456オッケー、出口8オッケー、123ドア、ノー・スモーキングのじゃ。
Next is 3. 1-6 okay, Exit 8 okay, 3 doors, no smoking.
床もツルツルじゃないし、人間の顔を見るのじゃ。
The floor isn't smooth, and I'll watch the guy's face.
待っててあげる。待っててあげる。
I'll wait for him. I'll wait for him.
人間来るの待っててあげる。私優しいから。見られてない。
I'll wait for him to come. I'm nice. Not being watched.
見られてない。おじさんも大丈夫。
Not being watched. The old man is fine too.
よしよしよし、エイト歯科医院のじゃ。
Alright, Eight Dental Clinic.
アルバイトオッケーですのじゃ。分電盤室オッケーですのじゃ。
Part-time job okay. Electrical panel room okay.
ズイのじゃ。司法書士のじゃ。
Zui. Judicial scrivener.
メイクアップアートのじゃ。天井とかも何もないのじゃ。コンコースオッケー。
Makeup art. Nothing on the ceiling either. Concourse okay.
従業員専用、ムーヴフェイス。
Employee-only, Move Face.
防犯カメラ作動中！キャー！キャー！ごめん、肩凝っちゃった！
Security camera in operation! Ahh! Sorry, my shoulder got stiff!
びっくりした！助けて！何なのじゃ！？絶対変なのじゃ！
I was scared! Help! What is this?! It's definitely weird!
なんか音、なんか音、何の音か分かんなかった。
Some sound... I didn't know what kind of sound it was.
なのじゃ！なのじゃ！な、な、何の音か分かんなかったのじゃ！
What was that?! I didn't know what sound it was!
何 音か分かんなかったけどなんか来た！うう...
I didn't know what sound it was, but something came! Ugh...
ええ、逃げられた！逃げられた！怖いのじゃ！何なのじゃ！
Ah, I got away! I got away! It was scary! What was that?!
びっくりした！え、何が、何があったかもわかんない。何が、何言ってたのかもわかんない。
I was startled! I don't know what happened or what I said.
びっくりした、びっくりしたのじゃ。
I was startled, I was startled.
なんか、なんか、なんか、なのじゃ。
Something... something...
え、違うの、一時停止！一時停止！一時停止を押したつもりもなく、なんかびっくりして、びっくりして、キーボードぶわって押したら、キーボード、キーボードバーンって押したら、なんか画面止まったのじゃ！画面止まったのじゃ！びっくりしたのじゃ！
Wait, pause! Without meaning to, I panicked and hit the keyboard, and the screen froze!
水の、水の、行った、行った水！なのじゃ。
Water, water, I drank water! Oh man.
ねえどうしよう、これってさ、これであたしがさ、本当は可愛くないのにうしろにバレちゃったらどうしよう。
What if people realize I'm not actually cute behind me?
ねえ、あたしがさ、お尻、お尻、お尻の先美声をさ、聞いてさ、お尻がさ、お尻がさ、あー、なんか、め、目の先美声可愛くなくていへんとか思ったらどうしよう？
What if they think my voice isn't cute? What should I do?
なのじゃ！頑張って、家に喜んで欲しくって頑張って可愛いやってるのに、叫んでるとこで可愛くないって思われたらどうしよう。
I'm trying hard to be cute, what if you think I'm not when screaming?
なのじゃ... その時は引き返してみる？進んで欲しいのじゃ！引き返さないでほしいのじゃ！あたしの声が可愛くないって思っても引き返さないでほしいのじゃ！共に諦めて、諦めて共に一緒に歩んでほしいのじゃ！諦めてほしいのじゃ！
Even if you think my voice isn't cute, don't turn back! Walk together with me!
よし、3行くのじゃ！ふう、3行くのじゃ。
Alright, let's go to 3! Whew, let's go to 3.
123456、出口8、ツルツルじゃない、えっと、禁煙オッケーのじゃ。
123456, Exit 8, not slippery, um, no smoking okay.
えっと、じゃあおじさんをゆっくり見よう。エイト歯科医院オッケーのじゃ。
Um, let's slowly look at the old man. Eight Dental Clinic okay.
おじさん、おじさん、オッケー。おじさんオッケーそう。おじさんオッケーそうなのじゃ。
Old man, old man, okay. The old man seems okay.
歯科医院アルバイト募集、分電盤室。
Dental clinic part-time job opening, electrical panel room.
オープン、ドッグサロンZUI、司法書士、司法書士オッケー。
Open, Dog Salon ZUI, judicial scrivener, judicial scrivener okay.
メイクアップオッケー、えっと、ムーヴフェイスオッケー、防犯カメラオッケー。
Makeup okay, um, Move Face okay, security camera okay.
天井も見るのじゃ。地下広場、異変なし。
Check the ceiling too. Underground plaza, no anomaly.
分電盤室、従業員専用、清掃員室、清掃員室詰め所。
Electrical room, employee-only, cleaner room, cleaner room office.
えっと、消火栓オッケー。
Um, fire hydrant okay.
異変見えない。よしよしよしよし。
No anomaly in sight. Alright, alright.
大丈夫。後ろ向いても、下向いても大丈夫。大丈夫なのじゃ。
It's fine. Looking back, looking down is fine. It's fine.
うん、大丈夫。
Yeah, it's fine.
行くのじゃ。
Let's go.
よし、次は行けるんじゃ。
Alright, I can go next.
4！4番なのだ。
4! Number 4.
4番なのだ。
Number 4.
おーい、びっくりさせないでほしいのじゃ。
Hey, please don't scare me like that.
びっくりさせないでほしいのじゃ。
I said don't scare me.
よしよしよしよし、折り返し！半分なのだ。
Okay, okay, okay. Turning back! It's halfway.
行くのだ。
Let's go.
ちらっ。
Peek.
うおっ、2人いるのだ！なに！
Whoa, there are two of them! What?!
2人いた！2人いたのだ！
There were two! There were two!
ダブル。
Double.
サイクロン浄化なのだ！
Cyclone purification!
ううっ、怖い！えっ、なんか、これさ、2人いると思ってすぐ逃げなかったら絶対2人がかりでわしのこと……
Ugh, scary! If I hadn't run away immediately thinking there were two, they would've ganged up on me...
2人掛かりで、わしのこと、わしのこと、捕まえようとしてるんじゃろう。
They would've ganged up and tried to catch me, right?
うう、びっくり！びっくりしたのだ！
Ugh, scary! I was startled!
でも5、でも5、でも5なのだ。
But it's 5, but it's 5, but it's 5.
分かりやすい、分かりやすい異変はありがたいのじゃ。
Easy-to-understand anomalies are a blessing.
分かりやすい異変はありがたいのじゃ。
Clear anomalies are such a relief.
すぐ逃げることができるからな。
Because I can run away right away.
ちらっ。
Peek.
ちらっ。123456オッケー。
Peek. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, okay.
お部屋も3つあるのじゃ。
There are 3 rooms too.
禁煙もある？
No smoking too?
禁煙もある。
No smoking too.
おじさんの顔を見させていただきますのじゃ。
Let me take a look at the old man's face.
おじさんの顔？
The old man's face?
お顔見せて。
Show me your face.
お顔も大丈夫なのだ。
Your face is fine too.
お背中も大丈夫ですのじゃ。
Your back is fine too.
床もツルツルじゃないですのじゃ。
The floor isn't slippery either.
はい、歯科医院オッケー。
Yes, dental clinic, okay.
歯科医院オッケー。
Dental clinic okay.
アルバイトオッケー。
Part-time job okay.
ろく？
Six?
ろくオッケー、犬オッケー。
Six okay, dogs okay.
分電盤室オッケー。
Distribution board room okay.
えっと、司法書士オッケー。
Um, judicial scrivener, okay.
えっと、メイクアップオッケー。
Um, makeup, okay.
ムーヴフェスオッケー。
Move Fes, okay.
防犯カメラもオッケーですのじゃ。
Security camera is also okay.
地下広場？
Underground concourse?
天井もオッケーそう。
Ceiling looks okay too.
床もオッケーそう。
Floor looks okay too.
消火栓オッケー。
Fire hydrant okay.
防犯カメラもある。
Security camera's there too.
6、シックスのじゃ！
6, number 6!
あと2個、あと2個！あと2個、あと2個！
2 more, 2 more! 2 more, 2 more!
のじゃ。
you know.
ちょっと、ここで、ここで絶対に決めるのじゃ！ここで絶対に決めますのじゃ！
Wait, I'm definitely going to decide it here! I'll definitely decide it here!
覚えた！完全にすべてを。
I memorized it! Completely everything.
はい、おじさんオッケー。おじさんいるのじゃ。
Yes, old man okay. The old man is there.
ツルツルじゃない。床オッケー。
Not slippery. Floor okay.
天井オッケー。
Ceiling okay.
禁煙オッケー。
No smoking okay.
おじさん見ますのじゃ。123456オッケー。
Let's check the old man. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, okay.
おじさん見して、わしのこと見てない。
Looking at the old man, he's not looking at me.
わしに興味ないおじさん。
An old man who has no interest in me.
オッケー。
Okay.
エイト歯科医院オッケー。
Eight Dental Clinic okay.
アルバイトオッケー。
Part-time job okay.
ドックランオッケー。
Dog run okay.
分電盤室オッケー。
Distribution board room okay.
上を見る。地下広場。
Look up. Underground concourse.
もっと上を見る。天井、顔ない。
Look further up. Ceiling, no face.
司法書士オッケー。
Judicial scrivener okay.
メイクアップオッケー。
Makeup okay.
ムーヴフェスオッケー。
Move Fes okay.
従業員オッケー。
Employee okay.
防犯カメラオッケー。
Security camera okay.
うん、いいんじゃないか？
Yeah, isn't this good?
よし、消火栓もある。
Alright, there's a fire hydrant too.
消火栓もある。
Fire hydrant is there too.
うん、大丈夫。進むのだ！
Yeah, it's fine. Let's move forward!
のじゃー！7、7、7なのだ！
No way! 7, 7, number 7!
いやあ、早いもので、早いもので1時間、皆様にお付き合いいただき
Man, time flies, thank you all for keeping me company for an hour...
まじだけどね
It's for real, though.
わしの旅もそろそろ終わりそうリスのじゃ
My journey is also coming to an end soon.
もうさすがに見落とさないのじゃ
I won't miss anything anymore.
覚えたのじゃ
I've memorized it.
こんだけやれば覚えるのじゃ
If I do this much, I'll remember it.
いくら記憶力のないタイプのサラマンダーだとはいえばどいけますのじゃ
Even if I'm a salamander with zero memory, I can do this!
よし
Alright.
床オッケー？
Floor okay?
床オッケー床オッケー
Floor okay, floor okay.
ノーモスキーティングオッケー？
No smoking okay?
おじさんの顔を見せていただきますのじゃ
Let me see the old man's face.
見して見してのじゃ
Show me, show me.
お顔オッケー
Face okay.
お顔大丈夫
Face is fine.
背中も大丈夫、スマホも持ってる
Back is fine, he has his phone.
よし
Alright.
行くのじゃ
Let's go.
何度も見たげのじゃ
I've seen this so many times.
アルバイトパート大募集！
Part-time job massive recruitment!
何度も見た
Seen it many times.
時給が1000円
Hourly wage 1,000 yen.
あ
Ah.
お顔ある
There's a face.
ねえお前らお顔ある！
Hey guys, there's a face!
わしもやったこれ、お顔ある！
I already did this, there's a face!
お顔あるお顔ある！
There's a face, there's a face!
はちー！
Eight!
88、エイト
88, Eight.
はあ、早いもので
Haa, time flies.
8番出口ですか
Is this Exit 8?
8番に来ましたのじゃ
I've come to Exit 8.
それでは進ませていただきますのじゃ
Then I will proceed.
進ませていただきますのじゃ
I will proceed.
覚えゲーですのじゃ
It's a memory game.
ここで異変がなければ
If there's no anomaly here,
ノーモスキーティングオッケー？
No smoking okay?
床ツルツルじゃないオッケー？
Floor isn't slippery okay?
おじさんのお顔を見る
Look at the old man's face.
おじさんのお顔大丈夫そう
The old man's face looks fine.
わしのこと見てない
He's not looking at me.
スマホも持ってる、背中もオッケー
He has his phone, back is fine too.
8月8日オッケー？
August 8th okay?
アルバイトパート募集オッケー？
Part-time job recruitment okay?
ニューオープンオッケー？
New open okay?
分電盤室オッケー？
Distribution panel room okay?
司法書士オッケー？
Judicial scrivener okay?
メイクアップオッケー？
Makeup okay?
ムーヴフェスオッケー？
Move Fest okay?
防犯カメラオッケー？
Security camera okay?
消火栓
Fire hydrant
清掃員詰所3部屋だよね
Cleaner's office has 3 rooms, right?
3部屋だよね、従業員専用
3 rooms right, staff only.
上にもあるし、天井もないし
There's one above too, and no ceiling,
分電盤室あるし
There's a distribution panel room,
地下広場だし
It's the underground plaza,
エイト歯科だし
It's Eight Dental,
目日休みのエイト歯科だし
It's Eight Dental which is closed on Thursday and Sunday,
アルバイト
Part-time job
空白の使い方が違くなくない？
Isn't the use of whitespace different?
ドアと同じサイズじゃない？
Isn't it the same size as the door?
でもこんなでかかった気がするのじゃ
But I feel like it was this big.
なんか比率がおかしい
Somehow the ratio is weird.
画面の比率がおかしいのじゃ
The screen ratio is weird.
なんかこれ75%ぐらいだ気がするのじゃ、これのサイズの
I feel like this is about 75% of this size.
戻る！
Turn back!
戻る戻る戻る戻る戻る戻る戻る！
Turn back, turn back!
8！
8!
8、8なのじゃ
8, it's 8.
え？ん？8ということは、何？ん？
Huh? 8 means what? Huh?
これは間違いじゃないから8
This isn't a mistake, so 8.
もう1回遊べるドン！
Play again!
ほらね！こんなでかくなかっ...
Look! It wasn't this big...
ほら、こんなでかかったのじゃ！
Look, it was this big!
こんなでかくなったのじゃ！
It got this big!
おじさん、ん、まだ続くの？
Old man, hm, does it still continue?
おじさん見るのじゃ
Look at the old man.
おじさん見てない？スマホ持ってる
Old man isn't looking? He has his phone.
オッケー
Okay.
背中オッケー
Back is okay.
えっと 募集
Um, hiring.
分電盤室
Electrical room.
えー 随
Um, Zui...
司法書士 6枚あるからオッケー
6 judicial scriveners, so it's okay.
あ、待って待って待って！
Ah, wait, wait, wait!
待って待って待って待って！
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
何何何何！
What, what, what, what!
男、男怖いよ！男怖いよ！
A man, a scary man! A scary man!
やめて！やめて！やめて！何何何！
Stop! Stop! Stop! What, what, what!
え？何？何？怖い！何！
Eh? What? What? Scary! What!
え？長い、長い、長い！何何何！
Eh? It's long, long, long! What!
何？まだ続くの？何？
What? It's still going? What?
何のじゃ？
What is this?
水来た。
Water came.
怖い。
Scary.
怖いのじゃ。
It's scary.
水
Water...
水来た。
Water came.
おじさん見る。おじさん見る、おじさん、ワシのこと見てない、オッケー。背中も大丈夫？
Look at the old man. He's not looking at me, okay. Back is okay too?
あー、怖いのじゃ！
Ah, it's scary!
あまりにね、音に怯えて…音に怯えて…音に怯えて…音ビックリするからやめてほしいの。
I'm so scared of the sounds... so please stop startling me.
はい、8月8日、オッケー。
Okay, August 8th, okay.
1 2 3 4 5 6オッケー、アルバイトオッケー。
1 2 3 4 5 6, okay, part-time job okay.
分電盤室オッケー。
Electrical room okay.
出口8オッケー。
Exit 8 okay.
えー、司法書士オッケー。
Um, judicial scrivener okay.
天井も変なのない。
Nothing weird on the ceiling either.
メイクアップアーティストオッケー。
Makeup artist okay.
えっと
Um...
のじゃ？
What's this?
ムーブフェスオッケー。
Move Fes okay.
防犯カメラオッケー。
Security camera okay.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
また何！？また変なの付いてる！真ん中に付いてる！
What again!? Another weird thing is attached! In the middle!
異変なのじゃ！異変しかない！異変しかないのじゃ！
It's an anomaly! There's only anomalies! Only anomalies!
これ、これ何！？これ正解ないと帰れない感じなのじゃ！
What is this!? It feels like I can't go home without the right answer!
水、水飲むでいいのじゃ？水飲むのじゃ？失礼しますのじゃ。
Is it okay to drink water? Drink water? Excuse me.
疲れてないけど、びっくりしたののびっくりが、びっくりが体に残ってるのじゃ！
I'm not tired, but the shock is still lingering in my body!
びっくりして、あの、あの、びっくりしたのが体に残ってるのじゃ、水飲むのじゃ。
The shock is still lingering in my body, so I'll drink some water.
疲れてはいないのじゃ。ううー。
I'm not tired. Ugh.
よし。落ち着くのじゃ。行きますのじゃ。
Okay. Calm down. Let's go.
そろそろ帰りたいのじゃ。で、でも結構もう見たんじゃない？異変。
I want to go home soon. But haven't I seen quite a few anomalies?
結構いっぱいの異変見た気がしますのじゃ。
I feel like I've seen quite a lot of anomalies.
チラッ、チラッ。
Peeking, peeking.
ツルツルじゃない！ツルツルじゃない！
It's not smooth! It's not smooth!
ノーモーキング禁煙オッケー。
No smoking, okay.
ちょっとおじさんをね、待ちますのじゃ。おじさん。
I'll wait for the old man. Old man.
1 2 3、おじさん。
1 2 3, old man.
失礼しますのじゃ。おじさんワシのこと見てない、ワシにあまり興味ない。
Excuse me. The old man isn't looking at me, he's not interested in me.
背中もオッケー。
Back is okay too.
ええと、8月8日オッケー。
Um, August 8th okay.
8月8日オッケー、パートオッケー。
August 8th okay, part-time job okay.
1 2 3 4 5 6、分電盤室オッケー。
1 2 3 4 5 6, electrical room okay.
出口8オッケー。
Exit 8 okay.
随オッケー。随オッケー、随オッケー、随オッケー。
Zui okay. Zui okay, Zui okay, Zui okay.
えーと、疲れた！疲れたというかびっくりしちゃった！
Um, I'm tired! Well, more like I got shocked!
えー、司法書士オッケー。
Um, judicial scrivener okay.
メイクアップオッケー。
Makeup okay.
ムーブフェスオッケー。
Move Fes okay.
防犯カメラオッケー。
Security camera okay.
従業員専用、清掃員詰所、消火栓？
Staff only, cleaner's room, fire hydrant?
消火栓？地下広場？
Fire hydrant? Underground plaza?
え、これ、これ行けるんじゃないのじゃ？
Eh, can we go through here?
これいけるんじゃない？ちょっとこれでいけなかったら泣いちゃうからちゃんとやり直すのじゃ。
Can we go? If this doesn't work I'll cry, so I'll check properly again.
もう1回ちゃんと言い直す。地下広場。
Checking properly again. Underground plaza.
顔も変わってない。ドッグ、ノーモーキング貼ってある。
Face hasn't changed either. Dog salon, no smoking posted.
1 2 3、ドア1 2 3個ある。
1 2 3, there are 1 2 3 doors.
うん、1 2 6ある。
Yeah, there are 1 2 6.
ドアノブ、ツルツルじゃない！
The doorknob isn't smooth!
え、天井にも何もない！うん。
Eh, nothing on the ceiling either! Yeah.
え、これ来たのでは？
Eh, did we make it?
地下広場。
Underground plaza.
一応… 一応ね。
Just in case... Just in case, you know.
これ来たのでは？
Could this be it?
これ来たのじゃ？ 勝ったのじゃ。
Could this be it? I won!
それでは皆々、今までありがとうございましたのじゃ。
And so, everyone, thank you all so much up until now.
はあっ！
Haah!
出口！
Exit!
はぁ、本物の出口なのじゃー！
Haah, it's the real exit!
やったのじゃー！クリアー！
I did it! Cleared!
出口8！
Exit 8!
あー、明るい。太陽光を浴びなくて頭おかしくなってたのじゃ。
Ah, it's so bright. My brain was going crazy from not soaking up any sunlight.
うわあ、クリアー！
Whoa, cleared!
やったのじゃー！
I did it!
頑張ったのじゃ。
I did my best!
これなかなか…なかなか頑張ったのじゃ。
This was quite... I worked quite hard.
すごい怖かった！
It was super scary!
すごいびっくり多かった！
There were so many jump scares!
すごいびっくり多くなかった？
Wasn't there a ton of jump scares?
クリアしたのじゃー！
I cleared it!
何？異変コンプリートの旅って。
What? "Journey to complete anomalies"?
異変コンプリートの旅って何？
What is this "journey to complete anomalies"?
異変集めみたいなのができるの？
Can you collect anomalies or something?
見つかっていない異変が23個あります。のじゃ？
"There are 23 anomalies that have not been found." Huh?
ここからが本番？23個？まだあるの？
The real game starts here? 23 of them? There are still more?
じゃあ、もう1周ぐらいやっぱやるのじゃ。
Well, I guess I'll do about one more run.
ちょ、やる前に、一旦… どうしようかな。
Wait, before doing that, once... What should I do?
やる前に一旦、ちょ、今日出そうと思っていた告知を出していいのじゃ？
Before doing that, can I post the announcement I was planning to put out today?
ちょ、一旦告知をさせてほしいのじゃ。一旦遊ぶから。
Wait, I want you to let me make an announcement first. Because I'm going to play after.
遊ぶ前にちょっと…ちょっと待ってほしいのじゃ。ちょっと待ってほしいのじゃ。
Before playing, I want you to... wait just a moment. Please wait just a moment.
ちょ、一瞬Twitterでね、Twitterでの…
Wait, for just a second on Twitter, you know, on Twitter...
あの、お面かぶって、Twitterでの告知したいことがね、あったからね。
Um, putting on a mask, there was something I wanted to announce on Twitter, you see.
ちょ、それだけツイートさせてほしいのじゃ。
So, I just want you to let me tweet that.
ツイートだけさせてほしいのじゃ。
I just want to tweet.
遊びまくり例を日曜日にやるんじゃけど、それの告知をちょっとツイートだけさしてほしいのじゃ。
I'm doing the "playing-a-lot" stream on Sunday, but I want you to let me just tweet the announcement for it.
したのじゃ。
I did it.
もしらしたら下から、お主ら下から、あのリツイートとね、いいねしてきてほしいのじゃ。リツイートといいねしてきてほしいのじゃ。
Actually, from below, you guys from below, um, I want you to retweet and like it. I want you to come retweet and like it.
ちょっとリツイートといいねしてきてほしいのじゃ。
I want you to go retweet and like it.
で、もしその間にお手洗い行ってくるから、お手洗い行ってくるから、ちょっと待っててほしいのじゃ。
And, if you could wait a moment because I'm going to the restroom in the meantime, I'm going to the restroom.
お手洗い行ったら続きやるのじゃ。おまちくださいなのじゃ。
Once I get back from the restroom, I'll continue. Please wait for me.
ただいまーなのじゃー。
I'm back~!
お主ら、さっき出した告知、いいねとリツイートしてくれた？いいねとリツイートしたのじゃ？
You guys, did you like and retweet the announcement I put out earlier? Did you like and retweet it?
してくれたのじゃ？
You came to watch, did you?
してくれた人ありがとうなのはじゃ。
Thank you to those who came.
いつもでしたらわしはあんま配信時間長いタイプじゃないんじゃが、
Usually, I'm not the type whose streams are very long, but...
ちょっといけそうな気がしてきた。いけそうな気がしてきたから
I feel like I might be able to do it.
やってみるのじゃ。
So I'll give it a try.
うん、今日はね、あの、いつもね遊びまーりたいが配信する時、
Um, today, usually when Asobimaritai streams,
大体ね、およそミラが19時で20時からソピアで21時からつづりがやってきょうこが22時ぐらいとか、まあなんかそういう日もあったりするんじゃが、
roughly Mira is at 19:00, Sopia from 20:00, Tsuzuri from 21:00, and Kyouko around 22:00, or sometimes those days happen,
今日のはね、ソピアがね、23時のいつもの時間と違うのとね、つづりがね今日は休みだからね、
today Sopia is at 23:00, different from usual, and Tsuzuri is off today,
やっちゃおうかなと思って。
so I thought I'd do it.
やっちゃおうかなと思って、うん、
I thought I'd do it, um,
だから今日はやってみようかな？今日金曜日、確かに。
so today I'll give it a try? Today's Friday, that's right.
今日金曜日だし、やっていこうかなと思いますのじゃ。
It's Friday today, so I think I'll go ahead and do it.
いくのじゃ。
Here I go.
はい、見つかっていないが23個あるみたい。
Right, there seem to be 23 anomalies not found.
さすがにあの、あれね、23個全回収とかね、
As expected, um, you know, recovering all 23,
23個全回収は考えてないけど、体力許す限り
I'm not thinking of all 23, but as long as stamina permits
やるのじゃ。やらせていただきますのじゃ。
I'll do it. I'll take my time and do it.
覚えてきたし。
I memorized it.
ノースモーキングOK？
No smoking, OK?
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6
うん、うん。
Yep, yep.
のじゃ。異変なし。異変なし。
No anomalies. No anomalies.
異変なし。
No anomalies.
2周やるより会社の方が早い。
Doing two rounds is faster than work.
じゃあ回収していくのじゃ。異変ないのじゃ。
Well then, I'll recover them. No anomalies.
従業員専用、地下広場。
Employee only, Underground plaza.
うん。防犯カメラ？
Mm. Security camera?
異変ないのじゃ。
No anomalies.
異変見つけるだけだからね。
I just need to find anomalies.
もう1回クリアしてますからね。
I've already cleared it once.
こっち通ら、こっち通らね。
Take this way, take this way.
クリアしてますからね。
Because I've cleared it.
1、ナイスなのじゃ。
1, nice.
いくのじゃ。
Here I go.
123456、6つありますのじゃ。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, there are 6.
つるつるじゃないですのじゃ。
It's not slippery.
ちょっとお顔を見せていただいてよろしいか？普通なのじゃ。
Would you mind showing me your face? Normal.
え、今のは？今のバグ？
Eh, was that? Was that a bug?
今のバグ？今のわしの
Was that bug? My...
おまか？わしの環境？
My environment?
なんかノイズ入った！
Some noise got in!
ノイズ入ったけど。
Some noise got in.
異変ないのじゃ。地下広場。
No anomalies. Underground plaza.
異変ない。異変ない。
No anomalies. No anomalies.
え？異変ないままクリアする感じなのじゃ？
Eh? Are we clearing it without any anomalies?
異変ないままクリアする感じなのじゃ？
Are we clearing it without any anomalies?
2、なんか
2, somehow...
今になってごり薬担当が花開く。
Now fortune-telling's luck is blooming.
ねえ、わしの、わしのパソコンが良くなかったぽいのじゃ。
Hey, looks like my computer wasn't very good.
わしのパソコンね、ずっとね、良くないからの、
My computer, you know, has been not good for a long time,
ラグかったりしとるからの一変123456
lagging and stuff, so 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6
どうも3つある。ノースモーキングOK！
looks like there are 3. No smoking OK!
おじさん、わしのこと見てない。
Mister, you're not looking at me.
背中とかもオケーなのじゃ。
My back and everything is okay.
オッケーのじゃ。
It's okay.
防犯カメラOK？
Security camera OK?
おお、綺麗綺麗
Oh, very clean.
従業員専用...
Staff only...
従業員専用、おっ
Staff only, okay.
防犯カメラ作動中、おっ
Security camera in operation, okay.
どうじゃ？
How is it?
分電盤室
Electrical room
どうじゃ？
How is it?
の、の...
N-No...
どうじゃ？
How is it?
なんか...
Something...
なんかいった！？
Did something just move!?
こわい
Scary...
可愛くない？これとか言い直してほしいのじゃ
Isn't it cute? I want you to say it again.
のじゃー！
Noja!
のじゃのじゃのじゃのじゃ
Noja noja noja noja
気をつけよう。やっぱね、人間に可愛いって思ってもらいたいから
Be careful. After all, I want humans to think I'm cute, so...
気をつけよう。人間に可愛いと思ってもらいたいから、き、気をつけよう、のじゃ！
Be careful. I want humans to think I'm cute, so c-careful, noja!
頑張って人間に可愛いって思ってもらうと頑張ってるのに...
Even though I'm trying so hard to have humans think I'm cute...
気をつけよう、びっくりしないように、びっくりしないようにしよう、のじゃ。
Be careful not to be surprised, let's make sure not to be surprised, noja.
うん、禁煙ノー・スモーキングOK。
Yeah, no smoking OK.
123456OK？　ドア3つある。ドア3つある。
1 2 3 4 5 6 OK? There are three doors. There are three doors.
ええと、おじさん？おじさんね？
Um, mister? Mister, right?
私のこと見てない。
Not looking at me.
興味なさそう。
Doesn't seem interested.
後ろ向いてる。OK。
Looking back. OK.
エイト歯科医院OK、08/08オープンOK
Eight Dental Clinic OK, 08/08 Open OK
アルバイトパート大募集OK、ドッグサロンZUIオープンOK。
Part-time job posting OK, Dog Salon ZUI open OK.
のじゃ。
Noja.
ふふふふ、分電盤室OK。
Hehehe, electrical room OK.
うん、司法書士OK。
Yeah, judicial scrivener OK.
司法書士OK？
Judicial scrivener OK?
メイクアップOK？
Makeup OK?
ムーヴフェスOK、防犯カメラOK、ごはんカメラOK？
Move Fes OK, security camera OK, rice camera OK?
上も大丈夫。
Top is also fine.
床も、床も大丈夫。うん。
Floor is also, floor is also fine. Yeah.
消火栓もOKなのじゃ。
Fire hydrant is also OK, noja.
防犯カメラ作動中。
Security camera in operation.
ないの、異変？ないのじゃ！
No anomaly? There is none, noja!
ないのじゃ！
There is none, noja!
4！
4!
なんかすごいスムーズ、スムーズですのじゃ。
Somehow it's very smooth, smooth, noja.
のじゃ。123456、なんか数が減るとかあんまりないんじゃな。
Noja. 1 2 3 4 5 6, it's pretty rare for the number to decrease.
ドアの数が減る的なのはあんまりないんじゃな。ノー・スモーキングOK、出口OK。
It's rare for the number of doors to decrease. No smoking OK, exit OK.
床ツルツルじゃない、エイト歯科OK、そしてちょっとおじさん
Floor not smooth, Eight Dental OK, and a bit... mister.
お主をしっかりと、ぶりさんも何もないね。
Looking at you carefully... burisan also has nothing.
背中OKですのじゃ。
Back is OK, noja.
エイト歯科OK、アルバイトOK。
Eight Dental OK, part-time OK.
オープンOK、分電盤室OK。
Open OK, electrical room OK.
司法書士OK。
Judicial scrivener OK.
司法書士OK？
Judicial scrivener OK?
メイクアップOK？
Makeup OK?
メイクアップOK、ムーヴフェスOK、防犯カメラOK。
Makeup OK, Move Fes OK, security camera OK.
ムーヴフェスOK、防犯カメラOK、そして上を見る、地下広場OK。
Move Fes OK, security camera OK, and looking up, underground plaza OK.
何もないの、異変の、OKなのじゃ。
Nothing, the anomaly is OK, noja.
見た、もう一回後ろを振り向く、振り向くね。
Checked, turn around once more, turn around, right.
OKなのじゃ！
It's OK, noja!
進むのじゃー！
Moving forward, noja!
5！5なのじゃー！
5! It's 5, noja!
もう1回クリアしてますからね、わし。わしはね、1回クリアしてますからね。
I've cleared this once already, you see. I have cleared it once.
もう大体もう大丈夫ですのじゃ。下OK、ツルツルじゃないOK。
So basically it's already fine, noja. Floor OK, not smooth OK.
禁煙OKノー・スモーキング、エイト歯科OK。
No smoking OK, Eight Dental OK.
アルバイトOK。
Part-time OK.
おじさん、おじさんわしのこと別に見てない。背中も何もないね。背中OKですのじゃ。
Mister, mister isn't really looking at me. Back has nothing either. Back is OK, noja.
え、ドアいっこない！え、ドアいっこない！ドア123ってあったのにドアがいっこない！ドアいっこない！ドアいっこない！
Eh, one door is missing! Even though there were doors 1, 2, 3, one door is missing!
ドアいっこない！
One door is missing!
やっぱなくなる系もちょっとあるんだな。3つあったのに、分電盤室がないのじゃ！分電盤室が！
So there are cases where things disappear. Even though there were three, the electrical room is gone, noja!
分電盤室ない、行くのじゃ！
Electrical room is gone, let's go, noja!
1、2、3、1、2、3、4、5、6。ドアはあるの？
1, 2, 3, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6. Are there doors?
ドアはあるの？
Are there doors?
最初の通路、ツルツルでもないのじゃ。
The first hallway isn't smooth either.
エト歯科？
Eto Dental Clinic?
どうもどうも。
Hello, hello.
おじさん？
An old man?
おじさん別にワシのこと見てこない。普通のおじさんなのだ。
The old man isn't looking at me. Just a normal old man.
うん、普通ですなのだ。
Yep, totally normal.
アルバイトOK？
Part-time job OK?
お部屋OK？
Room OK?
ズイ。
Zui.
順番も別におかしいとこないのだ。
The order isn't weird either.
順番もおかしいとこなし。
Nothing weird about the order either.
天井もおかしいとこなし。
Nothing weird about the ceiling either.
下も、床もおかしいことなし。
Nothing weird about the bottom or floor either.
ないの？ 従業員専用。
None? Employee-only.
ないの？ なし。
None? Nothing.
え、なんかさっきより簡単なのだ？ さっきより簡単なのだ。
Huh, is this easier than before? It's easier than before.
7！
7!
7番なのだ。
It's number 7.
いやもクリアしちゃうけど。ワシクリアしちゃうけどいいの？
Well, I'm gonna clear it. Is it okay if I just clear it?
チラ。
Peek.
え、1、2、3ドアなし、1、2、3、4、5、6OK。
Uh, 1, 2, 3 no doors, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 OK.
よし。
Alright.
数はOK。
The count is OK.
通路、ツルツルじゃない？
The hallway isn't smooth?
おじさん見てるか。
Is the old man watching?
おじさん別にワシのこと興味ないみたいこのおっさんは。
This old man doesn't seem interested in me at all.
背中OK？
Back OK?
背中OK、エト歯科？
Back OK, Eto Dental Clinic?
アルバイト、オープン？
Part-time job, open?
分電盤室？
Distribution board room?
天井とかも特にないよね？ 天井とかも特にない？
There's nothing special about the ceiling either, right?
地下広場、壁？
Underground concourse, wall?
ふんふんふん。
Mhm mhm.
ないの？ 異変出ないの？
None? No anomaly appearing?
異変ないのじゃ。
No anomaly at all.
クリアしちゃうよ、ワシ、いいの？
I'm gonna clear it, is that okay?
ワシクリアしちゃっていいの？
Is it okay if I just clear it?
8！
8!
なんかするっといけちゃった。
Somehow I slipped right through.
1回目全然あれだったのに、するっといけちゃった。
Even though the first time was nothing like this, I breezed right through.
いいの？するっといけちゃって。
Is it okay to breeze through like this?
ラッキーなのだ。
How lucky.
行くのじゃ。
Let's go.
え？
Eh?
見ておヌシら！ なんか映ってる！ 向こうの壁になんか映ってるワシ見える！
Look at this, you guys! Something's reflected! Something's on the far wall, I can see myself!
なんかいる！
Something's there!
え、なんか、なんか映ってる！ なんか映ってる！
Huh, something's reflected! Something's reflected!
なんかめっちゃ監視カメラみたいなの映ってる！ ね、めっちゃ監視カメラみたいなの映ってる！
It looks like a bunch of security cameras! Hey, it looks just like security cameras!
見えない？ おもしろ見えない？ 見せてあげよっか。
Can't see it? Can't see it, you guys? I'll show you.
ほら。
Look.
なんか体あるよ！ 体あるのだ！ 体ある！
There's a body! There's a body! There's a body!
ほら！ 見て！
Look! Look!
体ある！ 体あるよ！
There's a body! There's a body!
こわい。
Scary.
こわいのだ。
It's scary.
こわい。
Scary.
びっくりしたのじゃ。
That startled me.
こわい。
Scary.
え、近づいたほうがいい？ よく見たほうがいい？
Eh, should I get closer? Should I take a closer look?
まあクリアしてるし1回近づいてみるか。
Well, I've already cleared it, so I'll try getting closer once.
まあクリアしてるしな。
I mean, I've cleared it already.
一旦ね。
For now, yeah.
え、こういう人ってさ、裸ん坊なのかなあ？
Uh, are people like this... naked?
裸ん坊で色塗ってるのかなあ？ 協力者がいるのかなあ？
Are they painted naked? Is there an accomplice?
うわあああああ！ お、追いかけてくる！ 追いかけてくる！ なんだお前！ なんだお前！ うわ、うわ！
Uwaaaaaah! It's, it's chasing me! It's chasing me! What are you! What are you! Woah, woah!
びっくりした！ びっくりした！
I was so scared! So scared!
近づくと！ 近づくと！ 近づくと追いかけてくるのじゃ！
When you get close! When you get close! It chases you when you get close!
近づくと追いかけてくるのじゃ！ びっくりした！ びっくりした！ びっくりした！
It chases you when you get close! I was so surprised! So surprised! So surprised!
チェイス中なのだ！
I'm in a chase!
追いかけっこなのだ！ え、あれ捕まってたら？
It's a game of tag! Wait, what if I got caught by that?
あれ捕まってたらどうなってた？ あれ捕まってたらどうなってた？
What would have happened if I got caught by that? What would have happened?
あれ捕まってたらどうなってたのじゃ？
What would have happened if I got caught by that?
びっくりしたー！
I was so startled!
初見で逃げ切った人初めて見た！ みんな逃げないの？
First time seeing someone escape on their first try! Don't people usually run?
みんな、配信者的にはぶつかるのが正解？
Everyone, as a streamer, is colliding the right answer?
配信者的にはぶつかったほうがよかったのかもしれんの。
As a streamer, maybe it would have been better if I collided with it.
怖かったのだ。
It was scary.
怖、怖すぎて。
Scared, way too scared.
ちょっとあれかのお、新人じゃの。ちょ、配信者的にはぶつかってたほうがおいしかったかもしれないの。
Maybe as a newcomer... As a streamer, it might have been better content if I collided.
怖かったのだ。怖、怖すぎて。
It was scary. So, so scary.
怖すぎて
It's too scary.
怖すぎて逃げちゃったのじゃ
I got too scared and ran away.
びっくりしたのじゃ
I was startled.
びっくりしましたのじゃ
I was really startled.
ふう、にしともびっくりした
Whew, Nishito was startled too.
よし
Okay.
よしよしよしよしよし
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
びっくりしたのじゃ
I was startled.
行くのじゃ
Let's go.
ん？
Hm?
どういうこと？
What does this mean?
何で逆なの？
Why is it reversed?
何で逆なのじゃ？
まっ
Wait.
ん？
Hm?
のじゃ？
Huh?
あれ、なんか0になってる！
Wait, it became 0!
え、なんか0になってる、なんで？
Eh, it became 0, why?
のじゃ？
Huh?
ん？
Hm?
あ！
Ah!
あの、追っかけてくる人が、追っかけてくる人が怖すぎて...
That person chasing me, the person chasing me is too scary...
のじゃ
so
逃げすぎたのじゃ
I ran away too much.
逃げすぎちゃった
逃げすぎちゃった！
I ran away too much!
怖かったのじゃ、だって
It was scary, you know.
だって、だって追っかけ回されるの怖いのじゃ
Because being chased around is scary.
こっ...
I'm...
追っかけ回されるの怖いから逃げる、普通に逃げるのじゃ
I'm scared of being chased so I run normally.
びっくりした
I was startled.
床オッケー
Floor is okay.
123、123456オッケー
1, 2, 3, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, okay.
びっくりした
I was startled.
おじさん見る
Look at the old man.
おじさんオッケー、ワシのこと見てない？
Old man is okay, isn't he looking at me?
だこと見てない、オッケー
Not looking, okay.
よしよしよしよし
Okay, okay, okay.
アルバイト
Part-time job.
サロン、ドッグサロン
Salon, dog salon.
天井もオッケー
Ceiling is also okay.
分電盤室オッケー
Distribution board room is okay.
うん
Yeah.
司法書士オッケー
Judicial scrivener okay.
なんかなさそうじゃの
Doesn't seem like anything.
地下広場オッケー
Underground plaza is okay.
うんうんうん
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
防犯カメラ作動中
Security camera in operation.
なーさそう！異変なし！
Seems like nothing! No anomaly!
異変なしっ
No anomaly!
よし
Okay.
えーっと
Um...
つるつるオッケー
Smooth floor okay.
天井オッケー
Ceiling okay.
禁煙オッケー
No smoking okay.
エイト歯科医院アルバイトオッケー
Eight Dental Clinic part-time job okay.
分電盤室もオッケー
Distribution board room is also okay.
おじさんも見る
Look at the old man too.
おじさんオッケーなのじゃ
Old man is okay.
うん
Yeah.
おじさんもオッケーそう
Old man seems okay too.
ポスターも
Posters too.
オッケー
Okay.
司法書士オッケー
Judicial scrivener okay.
順番も問題ないのじゃ
Order is also no problem.
ドアも3つ
Three doors too.
防犯カメラ
Security camera.
従業員専用
Employees only.
清掃
Cleaning.
ん、同じ
Hm, same.
上にもなさそうなのじゃ
Doesn't seem to be anything above either.
よし、オッケー
Okay, good.
行くのじゃ！
Let's go!
うんうんうん
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
お知らせ
Notice.
あと20個異変あるって
There are 20 more anomalies.
20個
20 items.
よし
Okay.
え？
Eh?
色が違う！
The color is different!
真っ赤なのじゃ
It's bright red.
これぐらいわかりやすかったらね
If it was this easy to understand...
ワシが一番最初にこのゲームは、その時もこれぐらいわかりやすくさ
When I first played this game, if it was this clear back then too...
初回でこれやってくれたらね、ワシだってね、ゲーム性わかった
If you did this on the first try, I would've understood the gameplay.
123456、123、うん、数問題なし
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 1, 2, 3, yup, count no problem.
ノーモッキング？
No smoking?
床ツルツルじゃない？
Isn't the floor smooth?
エイト歯科医院オッケー
Eight Dental Clinic okay.
おじさんも？
Old man too?
おじさんどうかな？
How's the old man?
おじさん大丈夫？
Old man okay?
出口8、分電盤室
Exit 8, distribution board room.
ズイ
Zui.
順番も問題ないのじゃ
Order is also no problem.
順番も問題ない、フーフェス、カメラ
Order no problem, Hu Fes, camera.
防犯カメラ
Security camera.
カメラ
Camera.
ドア
Door.
問題なさそう
Seems no problem.
天井も
Ceiling too.
天井も大丈夫
Ceiling is also okay.
よし、進む
Okay, moving on.
4なのだ！
It's 4!
まだまだいけるのじゃ
Still can go on.
あと19個
19 more.
よいしょよいしょ
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
チラ
Glance.
123456ある、ドアも3つある、よし
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 there, 3 doors too, okay.
床もツルツルじゃない！
The floor is smooth too!
ノーモッキングオッケー
No smoking okay.
エイト歯科医院オッケー
Eight Dental Clinic okay.
え、歯科医院
Uh, dental clinic.
アルバイト募集。
Part-time job posting.
おじさんわし見とるな
That old man's watching me.
おじさんわしのこと見とるな
He's really keeping an eye on me.
おじさんわしめっちゃ見とるな
He's staring right at me.
逃げる
Run!
5番！
Exit 5!
これが見てくるおじさん
That's the staring old man.
めっちゃ見られた
He stared right at me.
見られたのじゃ
He sure did.
今日もあんるのかな、わしに
Wonder if he'll be there again.
1、2、3、4、5、6、つるつるじゃない
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6... not smooth.
1、2、3ドアオッケー
1, 2, 3 doors, okay.
ノーsmoking
No smoking.
えっと、エイト歯科医院
Um, Eight Dental Clinic.
分電盤1つ、ふむふむ
One distribution board, I see.
おじさんもう見えてこなくなっちゃった。わしのこと嫌いになった？
The old man stopped appearing. Did he start hating me?
わしのことどうでも良くなっちゃったのじゃ？
Did he stop caring about me?
好きの反対は無関心なのじゃ？悲しいの、切ないの
Is the opposite of love indifference? So sad, so heartbreaking.
でも人間は心うつりするもの、わしに
But human hearts wander.
それに対してどうこう言うことはできねえすのじゃ
There's nothing I can really say to that.
ふむ。意見はなさそうかな、天井床。うん、大丈夫
Hmm, ceiling and floor look fine. Yep, all good.
ない！
None!
6、6なのだじゃ！
It's 6! Exit 6!
行くのじゃー！
Let's go!
1、2、3、4、5、6。1、2、3。ドアの数とかオッケー、床もオッケー
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6. 1, 2, 3. Door count okay, floor okay.
ノーsmoking、えっと、エイト歯科医院
No smoking. Um, Eight Dental Clinic.
アルバイト募集、おじさんみる
Part-time job posting. Old man...
おじさんみた、背中もオッケー
The old man saw me, back is fine too.
オープン、司法書士
Open, judicial scrivener.
のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
走れないの？走れないの？
Can't I run? Can't I run?
走る走る走る走る！走る走る走る走る！
Run, run, run, run! Run, run, run, run!
うっ、びっくりした
Phew, that scared me.
あんまり怖い音出すのやめるのじゃ
Stop making such scary sounds!
Stop making such terrifying sounds!
びっくりした
I got startled.
チカチカするの怖いのだじゃ
Those flashing lights are scary.
1、2、3、4、5、6。1、2、3。禁煙ノーsmoking、床つるつるじゃない
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6. 1, 2, 3. No smoking, floor isn't smooth.
天井、ん？曲がってる！曲がってるのだじゃ！
The ceiling... huh? It's bent! It's bent!
光が曲がってる！
The light is bent!
エイト、8！8！
Eight, 8! 8!
うおおお！これは分かりやすい！これは分かりやすく恐ろしいの
Whoa! This is so obvious! It's terrifyingly obvious!
怖いのじゃー
So scary!
あんま怖くないのを頼みたいんだが
I'd prefer something a little less scary.
1、2、3、4、5、6。1、2、3。ノーsmoking、床つるつるじゃない
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6. 1, 2, 3. No smoking, floor isn't smooth.
エイト歯科医院、アルバイト募集
Eight Dental Clinic, part-time job posting.
おじさん、おじさんの異変もなし
Old man... no anomalies with the old man.
後ろ大丈夫？
Behind me, okay?
ニューオープン
New open.
司法書士、メイクアップ、ムーヴフェス
Judicial scrivener, makeup, Move Fest.
これクリアしちゃうんじゃない？
Aren't we going to clear this?
Are we going to clear it?
クリアー！
Cleared!
2回目クリアーのじゃー！
Cleared for the second time!
異変あんま見つかんないの
Didn't find many anomalies.
異変が思ったより
The anomalies were more...
やっぱね、ごりやく担当すぎてね
Well, you see, I was too busy relying on divine favor...
ちょっと運がね、良すぎなのだじゃ
My luck was just a bit too good.
運が良すぎて見つけまくっちゃうのじゃ
I kept finding them because my luck is too good.
あんま異変なかった
There weren't many anomalies.
わしの幸運さ
My good fortune...
もう1回行ってみるのじゃ
Let's try going once more.
あと18？18とか17とか、それぐらいな気がする
Another 18? 18 or 17, feels around there.
それぐらいな気がするけど見っかんないの
Feels like that many, but I can't find them.
RTA? RTAってできるのじゃ?
RTA? Can you do an RTA?
気持だけ 気持だけね RTAの気持でやってみよう。
Just a feeling... let's try doing it with an RTA mindset.
RTA勢じゃ！しゃ、しゃ。
RTAers! Shh, shh.
お、RTA勢っぽい動き！しゃしゃしゃしゃしゃしゃしゃしゃ！
Oh, RTAer-like movement! Sh-sh-sh-sh-sh-sh-sh!
位置...
Position...
RTA勢っぽい動きをしてみた。どうじゃ？
Tried moving like an RTAer. How was that?
これで普通に見落としそうなんだが。普通に見落としそうなんだが、司法書士。1、2、3。
I'd normally overlook this... Judicial scrivener. 1, 2, 3.
うん。2、3大丈夫。
Yeah. 2, 3 are fine.
え、ない。異変ないのじゃ。異変なーい！
Huh, nothing. No anomaly. No anomaly!
に、異変なーい！
N-, no anomaly!
ノー・スモーキング、床大丈夫。ふむふむ、ふむふむ。
No smoking, floor is fine. Hmm hmm, hmm hmm.
異変なーい。ずい。どうじゃ、どうじゃ。1、2、3、4、5、6。
No anomaly. Zui. How is it? 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
異変なーいの。なーい！どうじゃ。どうじゃ、どうじゃ。
No anomaly. N-no! How is it? How is it?
んー、なさそう。なーい！
Hmm, looks like none. N-no!
もう一回見る。なーい！3！
Looking again. No! 3!
ふむ。床平気？禁煙平気？1、2、3、4、5、6、1、2、3。うん。なーい！
Hmm. Floor okay? No smoking? 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 1, 2, 3. Yeah. No!
おじさん... おじさんこんなでかかったっけ？おじさんこんなでかかった？でかくないのじゃ？
Old man... Was this old man so big? Wasn't he big?
覚えてないけどこんなでかかった気がする。
I don't remember, but I feel like he wasn't this big.
4! したたたたたたたたた！
4! Sh-sh-sh-sh-sh-sh-sh!
どうじゃ、どうじゃ。床ツルツル。
How is it? Floor is slippery smooth.
ある、だよね、おじさんのサイズだよね。
There is, right? It's the old man's size, right?
異変ないの？異変ないの？なーい！
No anomaly? No anomaly? N-no!
なーい！なーのじゃ！5なのじゃ！
N-no! It's-! It's number 5!
よいしょ！1、2、3、4、5、6、1、1、2、3。うん、床オッケー？
Yoishou! 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 1, 2, 3. Yeah, floor okay?
天井も大丈夫そう。1、8歯医者。2、アルバイト募集。うん。3、オープン。
Ceiling looks fine. 1, 8 dental clinic. 2, job opening. 3, open.
分電盤室。うん。おじさん見るのじゃ。おじさんも... なし。
Distribution board room. Yeah. Looking at the old man. Also... none.
地下広場。ないのじゃ異変。え、なんでこんなないの？
Underground plaza. No anomaly. Huh, why is there none like this?
なんでこんなないのじゃ？なーい！6！
Why is there none like this? N-no! 6!
よいしょ！1、2、3、4、5、6。禁煙、ツルツルじゃない。
Yoishou! 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6. No smoking, not slippery.
うん。8歯医者。1、2、3部屋ある。2、アルバイト募集オッケー？
Yeah. 8 dental clinic. 3 rooms. Part-time recruitment okay?
順番も合ってる。おじさん、おじさんも別に異変なし。
Order is correct. Old man also no anomaly.
屋上もない。1、2。なーい！
No roof either. 1, 2. N-no!
異変なーい。あ、ある！これついてなかった！戻る戻る戻る戻る！
No anomaly. Ah, there is! This wasn't on! Go back!
ついてなかった！あるー！なーのじゃ！7！
It wasn't on! There is! It's-! 7!
禁煙、ノー・スモーキング、床ツルツルじゃない。1、2、3、4、5、6、1、2、3。
No smoking, floor not slippery. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 1, 2, 3.
ドアの数は大丈夫なのじゃ。1、2、3。分電盤室。
Door count is fine. 1, 2, 3. Distribution board room.
おじさん見る。おじさん。おじさんも異変なし。
Look at the old man. Old man. Also no anomaly.
なし。1、2、3、4、5、6。部屋も特に異常なし。
None. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6. Rooms also no abnormalities.
ないのじゃ。なーい！なーのじゃ！
There isn't. N-no! It's-!
8! あと何個？13個。あんま見つかんないのじゃ。
8! How many more? 13. They aren't found much.
よいしょ。1、2、3、4、5、6。1、2、3。ドアの数問題なし、禁煙、床ツルツルじゃない。
Yoishou. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6. 1, 2, 3. Door count fine, no smoking, floor fine.
天井大丈夫。8歯医者。
Ceiling okay. 8 dental clinic.
アルバイト募集。分電盤室。おじさんは…おじさんも大丈夫。
Part-time job posting... 0-yen room. The old man is... The old man is fine, too.
オープン。うん。
Open. Hm.
異変なし。従業員専用。
No anomalies. Employee-only...
ふんふんふん。
Hm, hm, hm.
異変なし。うん。
No anomalies. Hm.
後ろから見ても大丈夫。床も…うん。
Looks fine from behind, too. The floor is... Hm.
なーい！
None!
ん？
Hm?
えっ、あったの？ 何？
Eh? What was that? What?
あったっぽい！あったっぽい！
There was something! There was something!
何が異変だったんだろう。なんだろ。あ、ここじゃない。あ、防犯カメラ作動中がここじゃなかった！
What was out of place? What could it be? Oh, wait, the security camera's active!
あー……
Ah...
盲点でしたのじゃ。
That was an anomaly, then.
盲点でしたのじゃ！もっと異変見つけるのじゃ！
That was an anomaly, then! I found another anomaly!
よいしょ。でも怖くなってきた。
Wait, it's getting scary.
112311123456。床平気。
1 1 2 3 1 1 1 2 3 4 5 6. Floor is normal.
確かにポスターなかったな。
That's right, there was no poster.
そのへんも覚えなきゃ。地下広場。おじさん…
I need to remember that area, too. Concourse. The old man...
のじゃ。うん、おじさんも変じゃないし。
No, the old man isn't acting weird either.
うん。異変なし。大丈夫そう。
No anomalies. Looks fine.
大丈夫そう！
Looks fine!
1！のじゃのじゃのじゃのじゃのじゃのじゃ！
1! No anomalies, no anomalies, no anomalies!
123456床平気。禁煙平気。
1 2 3 4 5 6. Floor is normal, smoking is prohibited.
123ドア平気。123456
1 2 3 doors are normal. 1 2 3 4 5 6...
おじさんも平気。
The old man is normal, too.
え、止まった。えっ、え、何？絶対追いかけてる！絶対追いかけてきてる！
Wait! He's definitely following me. He's definitely following me!
なんかおじさん止まった！おじさん止まったのじゃ！のじゃ！はい、逃げろ！
The old man stopped! The old man stopped, didn't he? Run!
巻いていく！
Run away!
はあー。止まるの、止まる系ね。そういうのじゃね。
Phew... Stopping... Stopping-type... That kind of anomaly, right?
のじゃのじゃのじゃ。禁煙。
No anomalies. No smoking.
123456123。床平気。
1 2 3 4 5 6 1 2 3. Floor is normal.
つるつるでもないね。つるつるでもない。
Not slippery. Not slippery either.
おじさんは止まらない。
The old man doesn't stop.
天井もない。ドアノブも大丈夫。
Ceiling is normal. Door knobs are normal.
うん。なーんない。
No anomalies. None.
のじゃ。3！
No anomalies! 3!
あと何個か。あと12個あるのじゃ！
How many more? 12 more, right?
よいしょ。123。
1 2 3.
床つるつるじゃない？123456。
Floor isn't slippery. 1 2 3 4 5 6.
番号大丈夫。うん、ズイ。順番も合ってる。
Numbers are normal. Zui... Order is correct, too.
おじさん。おじさんも平気。
The old man is normal.
ドアノブも大丈夫。
Door knobs are normal.
防犯カメラ作動中。
No anomalies.
なさそう。なさそう。
Nothing out of the ordinary.
なーい！
None!
よーん！
4!
123456123。ドアの数問題なし。
1 2 3 4 5 6 1 2 3. Number of doors is fine.
床平気。
Floor is normal.
後ろも平気。地下広場。
Back wall is normal, concourse.
おじさん。おじさんも平気。
The old man is normal, too.
ないの。
Nothing...
おわりわりわりわりおまえおまえ！おまえおまえおまえ！おまえーー！動いてるのじゃーー！
Wait, wait, wait! Hey, hey! Hey, hey, hey! Hey! It's moving!
異変なのじゃ！
That's weird!
よし。123456。禁煙。
1 2 3 4 5 6. No smoking.
うわっ！やばいやばいやばいやばいやばいやばい！のじゃのじゃのじゃのじゃ！暗くなるの嫌い！暗くなるの嫌いなのじゃ！
Ah, wait, wait, wait, wait! It's getting dark, I hate it when it gets dark!
ろく！
6!
うー！びっくりしたー。
Whoa! I was startled.
10こ。こわい。のじゃ。
10. Scary. No.
びっくり系が急に現れる感じね。なるほどね。
So sudden appearances are a thing. I see.
うん、禁煙。床つるつるじゃない123456。
No smoking. Floor isn't slippery. 1 2 3 4 5 6.
えっと、123。
1 2 3.
おじさんチェック？おじさんチェック？おじさんチェックオッケー？
Old man check. Old man check. Old man check, okay?
こわかったー。
Scary.
でもなんかこれはまた和室じゃの。
Wait, this is another... washitsu?
ない！異変なし！
No anomalies.
異変なし！
ななーー！
7!
よいしょ。123456。おま。禁煙。
1 2 3 4 5 6. No smoking.
床オッケー？天井もオッケー？
Floor is okay, ceiling is okay.
123おじさんチェック入るのじゃん？
1 2 3. Old man check coming, right?
おじさん。オッケー。
Old man. Okay.
よほっしょし。
Washitsu.
ない！異変なし。
No. No anomalies.
ムーブフェス。
Move Fes.
天井も見るのよ。天井も無い。
I'll check the ceiling too. No ceiling either.
うん、うん、うん。従業員専用オッケー。
Mhm, mhm, mhm. Staff-only area is okay.
うん。
Mhm.
ないの。うん。
None here. Mhm.
なさげ。のじゃー8！エイとエイとエイ！
Looks normal. No-ja, 8! Eight, eight, eight!
1 2 3 4 5 6.
1 2 3. 数はオッケー。ツルツルじゃない？ツルツルじゃない？
1, 2, 3. The count is okay. Isn't it smooth? Isn't it smooth?
エイト歯科？2。うん、オッケー。
Eight Dental? 2. Mhm, okay.
うん、オッケー。おじさんチェック入るのじゃ？おじさんもオッケー。地下広場。
Mhm, okay. Is an old man checking in? Old man is okay too. Concourse.
はーはーはーはー。お？違うポスター。
Ha-ha-ha-ha. Oh? A different poster.
違うポスターなのじゃー！
It's a different poster, no-ja!
のじゃー！かわいいウサギのポスターだったのじゃ。
No-ja! It was a cute bunny poster.
1 2 3 4 5 6. 1 2 3. うん、床もツルツルじゃない？
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6. 1, 2, 3. Mhm, isn't the floor smooth too?
1 2 3 4. おじさんチェック入るのじゃ？
1, 2, 3, 4. Old man checking in?
おじさん。のじゃー、のじゃー。
Old man. No-ja, no-ja.
うん、おじさんも大丈夫。これもないんじゃないか。
Mhm, old man is fine too. Isn't this missing too?
ない。なーい！
None. Non-e!
クリアー！のじゃー！
Clear! No-ja!
これ全部回収できる予感するのじゃ。まだ9時じゃし。
I have a feeling I can collect all of these. It's still 9 o'clock.
まだ9時じゃし。もう1回行くのじゃ。もう1回回収するのじゃ。
Still 9 o'clock. I'll go again. I'll collect them again.
なんか8番出口のプロになれる気がしてきましたのじゃ。
I feel like I'm becoming a professional at Exit 8.
わし1回切りの短期記憶苦手じゃけど、こんだけ何回も見たらさすに覚えられる気がしてきましたのじゃ。いけるのじゃ。
I'm bad at one-off short-term memory, but seeing it this many times makes me feel like I can finally remember it. I can do it.
確かクリアしないで異変引き返してもいいかも。確かに確かに。
Actually, maybe I can turn back at anomalies without clearing. True, true.
ベテランなのかな。あのね、わしねゲームねあんまり経験がないからね。
Am I a veteran? You see, I don't have much gaming experience.
ゲーム経験っていうのがさの、あのー、あんまりちっちゃい頃とかゲームやらないで育ったから、
As for gaming experience... you know, I grew up without playing games much when I was little,
そういう意味で、なんだろな。ゲームやらないで育ったからあんまりゲームに詳しくない。とこはあるんだが。
so in that sense, I wonder. Since I grew up not playing games, I'm not very knowledgeable about games to some extent.
やったら慣れる気がするのじゃ。やったら慣れそう。
I feel like I'll get used to it if I do it. I'll probably get used to it.
やったら慣れそうな気がするのじゃ。いくのじゃー！
I feel like I'll get used to it if I do it. Let's go, no-ja!
おおー！異変！同じポスター！のじゃー！
Whoa! An anomaly! The same poster! No-ja!
よいしょ。1 2 3 4 5 6 1 2 3.
Heave-ho. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 1, 2, 3.
ポスターオッケー。あ、ツルツル！
Posters are okay. Ah, smooth!
ベンチブロックがツルツルなのじゃ！引き返す！
The bench blocks are smooth! Turn back!
3。1 2 3 4 5 6 1 2 3. ドアの数オッケー。
3. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 1, 2, 3. Door count is okay.
よいしょ。8歯科、アルバイト募集、オープン。
Heave-ho. Eight Dental, part-time job recruitment, open.
おじさんチェック入るのじゃ。おじさん。おじさん大丈夫。地下広場。
Old man checking in. Old man. Old man is fine. Concourse.
防犯カメラ作動中。従業員専用、清掃員詰所。うん、これも大丈夫なのじゃ。
Security camera in operation. Staff only, cleaners' office. Mhm, this is also fine.
異変なし！異変なし！
No anomaly! No anomaly!
4！じゃじゃじゃじゃじゃ。
4! Ja-ja-ja-ja-ja.
1 2 3 4 5 6. 1 2 3 4 5 6.
1 2 3 4. おじさん見る？おじさんチェック？
1, 2, 3, 4. See the old man? Old man check?
おじさんオッケー。地下広場。防犯カメラ作動中。
Old man is okay. Concourse. Security camera in operation.
行くのじゃ！大丈夫そうな気がするけど。
Let's go! I feel like it'll be fine though.
大丈夫そう。行くのじゃ！異変見つけるのじゃ！
Looks fine. Let's go! Find the anomaly!
えーっと、床、天井、禁煙、1 2 3 4 5 6。
Um... floor, ceiling, no smoking, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
8歯科、アルバイト...
Eight Dental, part-time job...
お、おも
Wait, wait.
おじさん見る。
Let's check out the old man.
おじさん笑ってね？
Is the old man smiling?
おじさん笑ってるー！
The old man is smiling!
笑ってる気がするのじゃ！
I feel like he's smiling!
6！
6!
おじさん笑ってる。
The old man is smiling.
123456、禁煙
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, No smoking.
あ、反対だ！
Ah, it's reversed!
反対になってるのじゃ！
It's reversed!
看板が反対！
The signs are reversed!
あと5個だって。
There's 5 left.
あと5個。
5 more.
うんうん、禁煙、床、123456
Yeah, yeah, no smoking, floor, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
びっくりしたー！
That scared me!
何々何々何々？何この特、何この時を、時をと本当にびっくりするからやだ
What, what, what? What's with this— what's with this... It really startles me so I hate it.
時をと本当にびっくりするからやなのじゃ。
It really startles me so I hate it.
びっくりした。おきをと、おきをと怖いのじゃ。
I was startled. Watch out... it's scary.
ばくばくするのじゃ。123456
My heart's pounding. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
うん、確かにキックはデカければデカいほどいいて言ったけど
Yeah, it's true I said the bigger the better, but
そこまでデカくする必要はないのじゃ。
there's no need to make it that big.
なくない？ないの。
Isn't there? There isn't.
ない！
There isn't!
ゴールしちゃった！
I reached the goal!
次でいけるんじゃない？あと異変4とか、あと異変4とかだった気がするのじゃ。
Can't we do it on the next one? I feel like there were about 4 anomalies left.
だからそろそろもう全部見つかる気がするのじゃ。
So I feel like we'll find all of them soon.
わかってきた。
I'm starting to get the hang of it.
最初はね、最初はのクリアするたびにやっと、やっと地上に出れたって
At first, every time I cleared it, finally being able to reach the surface,
すごい嬉しくなってたのに
I was so happy, but
今となっては慣れてって怖いの、慣れていってプレッシャーがなくなっていくって
now that I'm getting used to it, it's scary—getting used to it means the pressure starts to fade away...
切ないの、切ないことなのじゃ。のじゃ。
It's bittersweet, a bittersweet thing.
恐ろしいの。
It's terrifying.
あと4個！4個ならすぐ見つかるんじゃない？
4 more! With 4 left, won't we find them right away?
4個ならすぐ見つかるんじゃない？
Won't we find them right away?
4個ならね。
If it's 4, yeah.
のじゃのじゃ。
Right, right.
おじさんも見るよー。
Let's check the old man too.
おじさん、オッケー？
Old man, okay?
おじさんオッケー？
Old man okay?
のじゃのじゃ。
Right, right.
天井とかもオッケー？
Ceiling and everything okay?
おじさーん、おじさーん！
Mister, mister!
よいしょ。
Here we go.
階段！
Stairs!
階段なのだーー！
It's stairs!
あれね、最初上ぼっちゃんたやつね、わしが。わしが最初上ぼっちゃんたやつなのじゃ。
That, you know, the one I climbed up at the very beginning. That's the one I went up first.
階段怖かったのだーー！
The stairs were so scary!
登っちゃった階段。
I went up the stairs.
大丈夫。
It's fine.
おじさん確認。
Checking the old man.
地下広場はオッケー。
Concourse is okay.
異変ないの？
No anomalies?
天井も大丈夫。
Ceiling is fine too.
異変なーーい！
No anomalieeees!
よーーん！
Four!
なんか明らかに違う。
Something's clearly different.
天井ブロックが違うのじゃ。
The ceiling blocks are different.
5ーー！
Five!
天井ブロックが違う。
The ceiling blocks are different.
おじさんチェック。
Old man check.
おじさん大丈夫？
Old man okay?
おじさん大丈夫。
Old man is okay.
監視カメラもある。
There are security cameras too.
うん。
Yeah.
監視カメラもある。
There's a security camera too.
大丈夫。
It's fine.
6ーー！
Six!
禁煙、ノー・スモーキング、123、123456、エイト歯科
No smoking, 1, 2, 3, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, Eight Dental Clinic
問題なし、問題なし。
No problem, no problem.
問題なし。
No problem.
うん、おじさん
Yeah, old man
うん、チェック入る？
Hmm, checking in?
おじさんチェックオッケー？
Is the old man check okay?
うん、大丈夫そう。
Yeah, looks fine.
天井も床も。
Ceiling and floor too.
大丈夫ー！
All good!
のじゃー！
Noja!
なのー！
Nano!
タバコ、ノーモキング８、1、2、3、4
No smoking, Exit 8, 1, 2, 3, 4...
おっ、なんか怖いポスターになってる。
Oh, it's turning into a scary poster.
ポスターが違うのじゃ！
The poster is different, noja!
最後のとこ、ポスターが違う！8ー！
The last part, the poster is different! 8!
えーっと、禁煙1、2、3、1、2、3、4、1、2、3、4、5、6
Um, no smoking 1, 2, 3...
おじさんの顔がバグってる。
The old man's face is bugged out.
おじさんの顔がバグってるのじゃ。
The old man's face is bugged out, noja.
びっくりしたー。
That scared me.
すべての異変見つけたって！
I found all anomalies!
すべての異変...あっ！
All anomalies... Ah!
追いかけてきたやついるー！
There's one chasing me!
のじゃー！
Noja!
えいっ、タバコ、床ツルツルじゃない。
Hey, no smoking, the floor is slippery.
1、2、3、4、5、6
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6...
上見る、ドア、おじさん
Look up, door, old man...
防犯カメラ、大丈夫そうかな？
Security camera, looks fine?
ゴールなのじゃー！
It's the goal, noja!
梱包もしたのじゃー！
Completed it too, noja!
やったのじゃー！
We did it, noja!
梱包しましたなのじゃ。クリアなのじゃ。
Packed it, noja. Cleared it, noja.
ありがとうなのじゃ。わしのね、ご利益のパワーで梱包して見せましたなのじゃ。
Thank you, noja. With my divine blessing's power, I packed and showed it, noja.
慣れって怖いの。
Getting used to it is scary.
すごい？早い？すごかったら高評価ボタンを押して、高評価してほしいのじゃ。
Amazing? Fast? If it was amazing, please press the like button and rate it, noja.
お願いなのじゃ。
I'm begging you, noja.
なかなか頑張りましたなのじゃ。
I worked pretty hard, noja.
やったのじゃ。
We did it, noja.
じゃあお部屋に戻ろうかのう。
Well then, shall we return to the room?
すべての異変が見つかりました。やったのじゃ！よいしょ。
All anomalies found. We did it, noja! Heave-ho.
おかえりー！
Welcome back!
のじゃー！
Noja!
怖かったけど、無事にクリアできましたなのじゃ。
It was scary, but I safely cleared it, noja.
びっくりするやつとかね、急に暗くなるやつとかは、すごく怖かったけど、楽しかった！楽しかったのじゃ！面白かった！
The ones that scare you or sudden dark ones were really scary, but it was fun! It was fun, noja! It was interesting!
面白かったのじゃ。なんか、びっくりするのはあったけど、
It was interesting, noja. There were things that scared me, but...
間違い探し。面白かったのじゃ。
Spotting the differences. It was fun, noja.
覚えたら、1回覚えたらこっちのもんですのじゃ。
Once you memorize it once, it's a breeze, noja.
楽しかったのじゃー！やったのじゃー！
It was fun, noja! We did it, noja!
お主らさ、お主らさ、あのさ、
You guys, you guys, you know...
わしが可愛くなくなっても嫌いにならないでくれる？
Will you not hate me even if I become less cute?
わしが叫ぶ時に可愛く驚けなくても、可愛く驚けなくても嫌いにならないでくれるのじゃ？
Even if I can't scream cutely or be startled cutely, will you not hate me, noja?
嫌いにならないで欲しいのじゃ。ちょっと人間に好かれたくて頑張って、
I want you not to hate me, noja. I tried hard because I wanted humans to like me,
人間が好きそうなのやってるのに、ちょっと怖すぎると、怖すぎると...怖すぎるとね...
and doing things humans seem to like, but if it's too scary, if it's too scary... if it's too scary...
どうしてもね、どうしてもね、我を忘れてしまいますのじゃ。
No matter what, no matter what, I forget myself, noja.
ててーん！えっと、明日は配信お休みですのじゃ。明日
Ta-da! Um, tomorrow's stream is a day off, noja. Tomorrow...
もお休みですが
Even though it's a day off,
10月の4日 日曜日なのじゃ、
it's October 4th, Sunday!
日曜日の20時から、
So on Sunday at 20:00,
遊びまわりたいデビュー記念歌枠リレーを
we'll be holding a debut celebration singing relay
行いますのじゃ。
where we play around!
20分ずつね、歌を歌ってね
20 minutes each, singing songs,
20分ずつ歌を歌ってね
singing songs 20 minutes each.
最後はね、あちちメラのチャンネルに集合してね、4人で歌うのじゃ。
And lastly, we'll gather on Aotchi Mela's channel and sing as four!
これをね、
This right here,
あちちメラのね、Twitterでね、あの、ツイートしたの、ツイートしたからね、
I tweeted about it on Aotchi Mela's Twitter, so...
あの、お主らね、リツイートとかね、いいねとかしてほしい。
I'd be happy if you guys retweeted it or liked it.
リツイートとかいいねとかしてほしい、な。
I'd really appreciate retweets and likes, you know.
わしすごい、八番出口すごい頑張ったから、リツイートとかいいねしてほしいな。
I worked really hard on Exit 8, so I'd love for you to retweet and like it.
してほしいのじゃ。
I really want you to.
きっとね、お主らが聴きたい歌も聴けると思う。
I'm sure you'll be able to hear the songs you want to hear, too.
あちちメラちゃんこの歌歌わないの？みたいな
Like, "Won't Aotchi Mela-chan sing this song?"
あちちメロ…にゃにゃにゃにゃ！あちちメラちゃん、この歌絶対歌うやろ！みたいな
Aotchi Melo... Nyanyanya! "Aotchi Mela-chan, you've gotta sing this song!" like that.
歌がきっとあるじゃろ？
There's definitely songs like that, right?
それをね、歌うので。
Well, I'll be singing those,
そう、それを歌うので
so yeah, I'm going to sing them,
聞いてほしい。楽しみにしててほしいのじゃ。
so please listen. I hope you look forward to it.
ちょ、ゴールドフィンガーね、
As for Gold Finger,
多分、あれ、元曲がね、海外の曲じゃからね、ちょっと難しい気がするのじゃ。
since the original song is an overseas song, it feels a bit difficult, you know.
うん、もちろんぞんじぬげてるんじゃが、いかんせんね、
Well, of course I know it, but even so,
そう、海外曲じゃからの。
yeah, because it's an overseas song.
うん。
Yeah.
あ、あとね、あとね、あとね！あとね、あとね！
Oh, and also, also, also! Also, also!
あのね、何だっけ？
Um, what was it?
ボイス！
Voice!
ボイス、ボイス、ボイス！
Voice, voice, voice!
ハロウィンボイス出たのじゃ！
Halloween voice is out!
YouTubeのコミュニティに詳細があるのじゃ。
There are details in the YouTube community.
ハロウィンボイス！
Halloween voice!
わしは四季をタント
I put a lot of heart into the seasons...
ハロウィンボイス聴いてほしいのじゃ。
I want you to listen to the Halloween voice.
頑張って撮ったのじゃ。初めてのボイス。
I worked hard to record it. My first voice pack.
きっとドキドキしちゃうと思うのじゃ。
I'm sure it'll make your heart flutter.
聴いてほしいのじゃ。
I want you to listen to it.
うん。こちらも
Yeah. This one too...
あの、Twitterとかにも
Um, there's information on Twitter and stuff,
情報があるので
so
お願いしますのじゃ。
please check it out!
あの販売ページに
On the sales page,
サンプル、サンプルもあるから
there are samples, so
サンプルをちょっと聴いて続きが聴きたかったら
if you listen to the sample and want to hear the rest,
ゲットするでも
getting it is fine too, I think.
いいと思いますのじゃ。
I think that'd be great.
よろしくお願いしますのじゃ。
Thank you very much!
あ、あと明日、明日秋葉原でね遊び回りたいのイベントがある。
Oh, and tomorrow, there's an event where I want to hang out in Akihabara.
明日と明後日ね、秋葉原でね遊び回りたいのね
Tomorrow and the day after tomorrow, there's an event in Akihabara where I want to hang out...
あのイベントがある。
an event, you know.
ボイスの感想タグはプロフィール、Twitterのプロフィールにあるんじゃが
The voice review tag is on my profile, Twitter profile,
あちち見てだっけ？
was it "Aotchi Mite"?
でお願いしますのじゃ。
Please use that!
遊び回りたいのイベントがありますのじゃ。
There's an event called "I Want to Hang Out".
ショッパー？なんかほら、コミケとかでもらえるさ、ショッパーあるじゃん。
A shopper? You know, like the paper bags you get at Comiket.
紙袋。あれがもらえる遊び回りたい版のあれがもらえるのじゃ。
Paper bags. You can get those "I Want to Hang Out" version paper bags.
無料。
Free!
あとスタンプラリーがあって
And there's a stamp rally,
スタンプラリーやると無料ですごい
and if you do the stamp rally, for free, you get...
なんか、なんだっけ？洗濯ネット？洗濯ネットがもらえるっぽい。
something like, what was it? A laundry net? You can get a laundry net.
遊び回りたいの絵が入ったやつ。
One with the illustration of "I Want to Hang Out" on it.
すごいじゃろ？
Pretty cool, right?
お楽しみに。
Look forward to it.
行けない地方民はあちちメラのハロウィンボイスそしてスターティングボイスを聴くのじゃ。
Regional folks who can't go can listen to Aotchi Mela's Halloween voice and starting voice.
ボイスを聴いてわしのことを考えるのじゃ。
Listen to the voice and think of me!
そう洗濯ネット貰うらしいのじゃ。
So you get a laundry net, apparently.
なぜ洗濯ネット？
Why a laundry net?
遊び回りたいのコンセプトがコインランドリーじゃからな気がするのじゃ。
Probably because the concept of "I Want to Hang Out" is a coin laundry.
うん、コインランドリーだから。
Yeah, because it's a coin laundry.
遠いお主らはボイスを聴くのじゃハロウィンボイスを聴いて…
Faraway folks should listen to the voice—listen to the Halloween voice...
そう、わしコスプレしたのじゃコスプレしたわしのボイスを聴くのじゃ。
That's right, I cosplayed, so you should listen to my cosplay voice.
明日は配信をお休みじゃからアーカイブを見直したり、あと何じゃ？
Since tomorrow is a day off from streams, you can re-watch archives, and what else?
なんじゃ？歌ってみたとかね、歌ってみたとかを
What else? Like listening to cover songs and stuff.
聴いてください。ハロウィンボイス、ヴァンパイアのコスプレしたのじゃ。
Please listen. Halloween voice, I did a vampire cosplay.
コスプレボイス、ヴァンパイアのコスプレしたのじゃ。
Cosplay voice, I did a vampire cosplay!
じゃあ今日は おしまい！
So today is the end!
お主ら一週間お疲れ様！
Good job on the week, everyone!
まあ土日も お仕事の人もきっといるだろうけど
Well, I'm sure there are people working on the weekend too, but
平日お仕事学校だったお主らお疲れ様！
to those of you who had work or school on weekdays, great job!
一週間お疲れ様んなのじゃ。
Good job surviving the week!
また次は何曜日かな？日曜日にえっと、遊び回りたいの歌枠リレーで…
And what day of the week is next? On Sunday, um, at the "I Want to Hang Out" singing relay...
お会いできたら嬉しいですのじゃ。
If I get to meet you, I'd be so happy.
20時からだからね、勘違いしないように。
It's from 8 PM, so don't get confused.
いつも19時だけど、
Normally it's 7 PM, but
20時からやるのでよろしくお願いしますのじゃ！
we're doing it from 8 PM, so look forward to it!
今日も配信はおしまいなのじゃ。
Today's stream is also coming to an end.
最後の挨拶は「さーばーじゃー！」でおねがいしますのじゃ。
Our final greeting will be "Saba jaa!", so please remember that.
お主ら行くよ？
You guys ready?
さーばーじゃーーー！！！
Saba jaaaaa!!!